大家请准备离船
Please prepare to exit the ferry.
甲板上请注意
Man: Attention on deck.
我们已经抵达火烧岛松林
We are now arriving at Fire Island Pines.
欢迎大家来到火烧岛
Welcome to Fire Island, everybody.
下船时请小心
Please take care exiting the boat.
楼梯可能很滑
Those steps can be wet.
另外请再次检查您的所有行李是否带齐...
Also double-check you have all your luggage...
祝您一天愉快
Have a good day.
- 嘿 威克斯 - 嘿 亲爱的
- Hey, Weeks. - Hey, honey.
还好吗?
How you doing?
我们都好极了
We're doing great.
到啦
Here we are.
你们在干嘛?
What are you guys doing?
露胸毛了哦 该到你了 泰迪熊
Hairy is out. Your turn, teddy bear.
不不 我喜欢我的胸毛
Oh, no, I love my teddy.
CK内裤不会赞同你
Calvin Klein would not approve.
棒球联赛已经开始
Baseball game is on
我的夏天正式到来了
and my summer has officially begun.
他可是说到做到
The thing is, he actually means it.
- 嘿 宝贝 - 你好吗?
- Hey, baby. - How are you?
- 冰啤? - 不了 我喝不少了
- Cold beer? - No, I've already had a couple.
条纹衫不赖啊 中尉 够性感
Nice stripes, Lieutenant. Hot.
拜托 叫人家队长
Oh, please... Captain.
刚从纽联储回来
Just got back from the Reserves.
知道人们怎么说吗 我每个月都能当一次大款了
You know what they say, once a month I get to play a real man
最近没怎么在健身房看到你啊
Oh, haven't seen you at the gym lately.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
- 到你了 布鲁斯 - 什么?
- Your turn, Bruce. - What? What?
布鲁西 亲爱的 别让我们的海景别墅丢脸
Brucey, please, don't embarrass our house at the beach, hon
啊哦 不刮不行了
Uh-oh. Gotta do it.
知道人们怎么说吗 内德
You know what they say, Ned.
不能打败他们...
If you can't beat 'em...
就加入他们
join 'em.
这就是我的男人
That's my guy.
你对他没兴趣时 克雷格伤心死了
Craig was miserable when you weren't interested
现在你看 他有了雷德福 (著名电影明星)
Now look. He's got Robert Redford.
说明上帝是存在的
Shows you there is a God.
- 约翰还好吗? - 约翰?
- How's John? - John?
- 约翰 - 噢 约翰啊
- John. - John? Oh, John.
不 我现在和格里高利在一起了
No, I'm with Gregory now.
我们要庆祝我们的15月纪念日
We're celebrating our 15-month anniversary.
15月? 对你来说很长了呀 米奇
15? That's a long time for you, Mickey.
拜托 我们是情侣 住一起
Oh, please, we're lovers and we live together.
不代表我们需要对彼此忠贞
It's not like we're faithful to each other, too.
他甚至不是犹太人 别跟我的犹太拉比说
He's not even Jewish. Don't tell my rabbi.
我的天
My God.
嗨 布鲁斯 你很烂
Hey,Bruce you suck
你干嘛还来这里?
Why do you even come here anymore?
我们不欢迎你
We don't want you.
你的小说很破坏我们形象
You made us look terrible in your novel.
看你周围 一片性解放
Look around you. Sex is liberating.
我只是说 太多的性爱会让寻找真爱变得不可能
All I said was having so much sex makes finding love impossible
别把你的情路失败找不到对象
Do not put your failure to find someone
- 发泄在我们身上 - 内迪!
- on the rest of us. - Neddy!
- 噢! - 我去
- Ow! - Oh, jeez.
我的天
Oh, God.
伙计们!
Guys!
嘿 怎么回事?
Hey, what happened?
- 你还好吗? - 我很好
- You okay? - I'm okay.
只是有点头晕
Just got a little lightheaded.
我能站起来 没事了
I got myself up. I'm fine.
我只是有一点... 晕眩
I just got a little dizzy.
他好像没事了
He seemed okay.
祝你生日快乐
? Happy bdadaday to you
? Happy birthday to you
祝亲爱的克雷格生日快乐
? Happy birthday, dear Craig
祝你生日快乐
? Happy birthday to you.
吹!
Blow!
他的强项哦
He's good at that.
我他妈爱死这地方了!
I fucking love this place!
"You Make Me Feel" (Mighty Real)
内德! 嘿 内德!
Ned! Hey, Ned!
来吗?
Come on. Please?
罕见癌症在41例同性恋中被确诊
平 常 心
Q
■
A
F
O
N
E
同志亦凡人中文站
我卖过一只陶瓷猪给你
I sold you a ceramic pig once
在巴勒克大街的法国艺术馆
at Maison France on Bleecker Street.
我叫桑福德
I'm Sanford.
是的 我记起来了
Yes, I remember.
我有个朋友在收集猪艺术品
Somebody I was friends with then collected pigs
而你有除真猪外我所见过最大的猪
and you had the biggest pig I'd ever seen outside a real pig.
它们在越变越大
They just keep getting bigger
而且不肯消失
and won't go away.
我是她的第20个病人
I'm her 20th case.
已经有6个死掉了
And six of them are dead.
嘿 内德 很快就到你
Hey, Ned. Won't be a minute.
巴兹 我不知道你在这儿上班
Hey, Buzzy. I didn't know you worked here.
你是谁?
Who are you?
内德·威克斯 "时报"文章后我联络过你
Uh, Ned Weeks. I spoke to you after the "Times" article.
进来 衣服脱了
Come in. Take your clothes off.
我只是来问一些问题的
I only came to ask some questions.
你是同志 对吗?
You are gay, aren't you?
对
Yes.
那就脱衣服 别紧张
Take your clothes off. Don't be nervous.
我见过的男体比你都多
I've seen more men than you have.
坦白说 关于你那些问题 我不知道
To answer all of your questions, I don't know.
我从没听过或见过这样的病症
I've never seen or heard of anything like this.
你有任何症状吗?
Have you had any of the symptoms?
"时报"上写的大多数东西...
Most of the shit the "Times" said...
阿米巴虫 淋病 肝炎
amoebas, gonorrhea, hepatitis.
你不懂性革命后我们的生活
You don't know what it's been like since the sexual revolution.
什么让你觉得我不懂的?
What makes you think I don't?
有发烧 盗汗 体重减轻吗?
Any fever, night sweats, weight loss?
做梦都想呢 没有
Don't I wish. No.
紫斑呢? 张开嘴
And purple lesions? Open your mouth.
这是种癌症
It's a cancer.
让免疫系统产生奇怪反应
There's a strange reaction in the immune system.
它崩溃了 不肯免疫
It's collapsed. Won't fight.
所以我的很多病人都被普通疾病击倒
So the diseases most of my patients are coming down with
而那些细菌原本是连婴儿都伤害不了的
are brought on by germs that wouldn't hurt a baby.
有点痒
Tick wlish.
总之纽约市的婴儿不会这样
At least not a baby in New York City anyway.
免疫系统是我们了解得最少的
The immune system is the system we know the least about.
我听说你有大嘴巴 它在哪儿?
So where's this big mouth I hear you've got?
- 大嘴巴是症状? - 不
- Is big mouth a symptom? - No.
是一种治疗
It's a cure.
这种病似乎只发生在男同身上
This seems to only be happening to gay men.
巴兹说你在同志群体中很有名
Buzzy says you are well-known in the gay community
想到什么就说什么
and not afraid to say what you think.
我找不到任何同志领袖
I can't find any gay leaders
我联系了同志组织 可没人回我电话
and I call gay organizations, no one ever calls me back.
布鲁克娜医生 只要有一半脑子的人都不会想牵扯进同志政治
Dr. Brookner, no one with half a brain gets involved with gay politics
- 没有指责的余地 - 你想指责什么?
- There's no room for criticism. - What's your criticism?
我厌倦了我们扮受害人
I hate that we play victim
我们中的绝大多数人都不需要
when many of us, most of us, don't have to.
那我们现在正用得到你
Then you're exactly what's needed now.
也许他们在等一个人来领导他们
Maybe they're just waiting for someone to lead them.
我不想领导他们
I don't want to lead them.
你到底想要试着说服我做什么?
What exactly are you trying to get me to do?
跟男同志说停止做爱
Tell gay men to stop having sex.
你觉得这个癌症是通过性来传播?
Do you think that this cancer is sexually transmitted?
我觉得是
I think it is, yes.
能证明吗 不能
Can I prove it yet? No.
你能意识到你在说的
Do you realize that you're talking about
是上百万的男人
millions of men
他们看重滥交
who have singled out promiscuity
并且把它作为一个基本政治纲领吗?
as their principal political agenda?
- 你要怎么应对? - 跟他们说可能会死
- How do you deal with that? - Tell them they may die.
- 哪儿? - 大厅尽头 大厅尽头!
- Where? - Down the hall. Down the hall!
不是这么简单 比这个要复杂
It's not that simple. It's more complicated than that.
他们认为性就是他们的全部
They think sex is all they have.
威克斯先生 如果做爱会杀死你
Mr. Weeks, if having sex can kill you
任何只要有一半脑子的人会不停止做爱吗?
doesn't anyone with half a brain stop fucking?
你可以走了 我没在你身上看到我想要的东西
You can go. I'm not finding what I'm looking for here.
- 哪儿? - 开门!
- Where? - Open up!
- 哪儿? 哪儿? - 那个房间
- Where? Where? - Right in that room.
把他放在桌上
Just put him up on the table.
这儿 我来查脉搏
Up here. Let's find a pulse.
亲爱的 冷静
Baby, easy.
- 别动 - 能告诉我发生了什么吗?
- Be still. - Can you tell me what happened?
我们在外面跟他会合
We were meeting him outside.
我们刚转过街角 他就发作了
We turned the corner and he just collapsed.
老天!
Jesus!
给我滚到路边去!
Hey, get the fuck out of the street!
亲爱的!
Baby!
- 我的天! - 救命!
- Oh, my God! - Help!
- 谁是他的爱人? - 是我 女士
- Who's the lover? - I am, ma'am.
- 你叫什么? - 布鲁斯·奈尔斯
- What's your name? - Bruce Niles.
我是布鲁克娜 我现在就需要一间病房
Brookner. I need a room immediately.
奈尔斯 你曾是莱因哈特的男友
Niles, you were Reinhardt's boyfriend.
是的 女士 你怎么知道?
Yes, ma'am. How do you know that?
他三周前去世了
He died three weeks ago.
他们甚至不让我跟他道别
Wouldn't even let me say goodbye.
不让我跟他吻别
Not even let me kiss him goodbye.
他死了?
He's dead?
真抱歉
So sorry.
它有这么快吗?
It can happen this fast?
就这样了
It just did.
我们得做点什么
We have to do something.
其他人都不会
No one else will.
我们能做什么?
What are we supposed to do?
你的假设只是建立在46个病例上面
You make these assumptions on the basis of 46 cases.
你想知道我怎么想 这就是我怎么想
You wanted to know what I think. This is what I think.
你们全部会交叉传染
You are all going to infect each other.
现在只有一部分人这样
Now only a few of you have.
遗憾的是 我们无法辨别哪些感染了
Unfortunately, we can't tell yet which ones.
早在我们隔离出肝炎病毒前
Long before we isolated the hepatitis viruses
我们也知道它们会带来什么
we knew about the diseases they caused
怎么传播的
and how they got around.
医学期刊怎么说? "时报"呢?
Where are the medical journals? The "Times"?
我一年前就把第一份报告寄给医学期刊了
I sent my first reports to the medical journals over a year ago
抱歉 你怎么知道你要找什么
Excuse me, how do you know what you're looking for
假如你不知道你要找什么?
real quick, if you don't know what you're looking for?
抱歉 可能我的这个问题很蠢
I'm sorry, I guess that's a dumb question.
不 不蠢 这是最聪明的问题
No, it isn't. It's the smartest question of all
只是回答它最难
and the hardest one to answer.
常识没有告诉你们 可以停止做爱一阵子吗?
Doesn't common sense tell you you should cool it for a while?
为什么不?
Why not?
这就没给我们多少盼头了
That doesn't leave much to look forward to.
万一事实证明你错了呢?
What if it turns out that you're wrong?
让她说!
Let her speak!
最糟的情形就是你们停止做爱一阵子
The worst that could happen would be that you cooled it for a while
不 抱歉 抱歉
No, excuse me. Excuse me.
抱歉 这不是可能最糟的情形
Excuse me. That is not the worst that will have happened.
人们会害怕做爱
Guys will become frightened of sex.
我们会失去长久以来通过斗争换得的自尊
We will lose our self-respect that we fought very, very hard for
我们会成为最糟糕的替罪羊
We will be scapegoated worse than ever.
全世界会认为我们是携带者
The world will think we're carriers
道德多数派绝对会开心死了
and the Moral Majority will have even more of a field day
这个轮椅贱人不走我就不回来
I am not coming back until this bitch on wheels is gone.
等等 我看过的病人一周比一周多
Wait. I see more cases each week than the week before.
有一半病人已经死了
Half of all my patients die.
希望她是说完了
Okay, I hope she winds this up
要知道新罗谢尔市正有个群交派对在等我
'cause I've got a tiny little orgy in New Rochelle.
卫生部在哪儿? 市长在哪儿?
Where's the health department? Where's the mayor?
- 闭上他妈的嘴 约翰 - 闭上你他妈的嘴 宝贝
- Shut the fuck up, John. - Oh, you shut the fuck up, hon.
数据是什么?
What are the numbers?
每个同志会议都是这样吗?
Is every gay meeting like this?
一半人到场是为了约炮
Half these people just showed up to get laid.
安静! 安静!
Quiet! Quiet!
我们要成立一个组织 我们要成立一个健康危机组织
We're starting a group. We're starting a health crisis group.
我们会再在这儿聚会
We're gonna meet here again.
下次准备些该死的食物
Next time, bring some fucking food.
嘿嘿嘿 这可不礼貌
Hey, hey, hey. That's not nice.
欢迎参与同志政治
Welcome to gay politics.
同志癌
他们具备如下一些症状
暗点状瘀伤
就像皮肤脱色一样的斑点
感觉不到痒或痛
身上任何部位都可能出现
我和克雷格·克莱波恩有个重要会面 我迟到了
Yeah, I'm very late for an important meeting with Craig Claiborne
他在等我
He's expecting me.
- 嗨 菲尼克斯·特勒 - 你是?
- Hi, Felix Turner. - And you are?
我叫内德·威克斯
My name's Ned Weeks.
你非常帅
You're very cute.
你找上我的时间不合适 好吗?
You caught me at a rough moment, all right?
我有交稿截止日期 第一夫人来纽约了
I have a deadline. The First Lady is coming to town.
我听说你是同志 而且你可能
I've been told you're gay and you might be able
会帮我在"时报"登出一些重要信息
to help me get some vital information in the "Times."
你"听说"? 听谁说的?
You've "been told"? And who was it that told you?
噢 亲爱的 人人都在说好吧
Oh, honey, everybody's talking about it.
为什么每个同志
Why does everyone gay
都觉得是我在经营”纽约时报"?
think that I run "The New York Times"?
我没法帮到你
I can't help you with this.
很抱歉听到 那你建议我怎么做?
Sorry to hear that. What would you suggest I do?
自己选吧 我写过23个派对
Take your pick. I got 23 parties
37家新餐厅 12家新迪斯科
37 new restaurants, 12 new discos.
听着 我没法让这儿任何人再写一篇相关报道
Listen, I can't get anyone here to write another article.
我跟半打记者聊过
I've talked to half a dozen reporters
包括那个写第一篇报道的人
and the guy who worked on the first piece.
"皮革先生"? 不
"Mr. Leather"? Yeah, no.
这儿没人会写这个 我也不能
No one here will write about it and I can't.
听着 我们这里分工很细
Look, we're very compartmentalized.
你不会想科学专栏来写羊毛衫 对吗?
You wouldn't want science to write about sweaters, would you?
让我感觉非常荒谬的是
It's a very peculiar feeling having to go out
我们必须求助于直人的世界来报道一点同志的东西
and seek support from a straight world for something gay.
这我就不知道了
I wouldn't know about that.
我只是碰巧写同志设计师 同志迪斯科
I just write about gay designers and gay discos
同志大厨 同志模特 同志摇滚明星
and gay chefs and gay models and gay rock stars
还有同志名人 同志一切
and gay celebrities and gay everything.
我只是不叫他们同志
I just don't call them gay.
正好是时候开始啊?
Isn't it time you start?
我有个交稿日期在等我
Look, I really do have a deadline
你也不想我被炒鱿鱼
And you wouldn't want me to get fired.
对吗?
Would you?
你这样的人最给我蛋疼
Guys like you give me a pain in the ass.
- 你写书的? - 没错
- You in the book? - Yes.
嗨 哥们 关注同志癌啊?
Hi, guys. Give to gay cancer?
嗨 关注同志癌? 不吗?
Hi, give to gay cancer? No?
嗨 关注同志癌吗?
Hi. Give to gay cancer?
先生...
Hi, sir...
嗨 关注同志癌吗? 在同志社群中有一种癌
Hi, give to gay cancer? There's a cancer in the gay community.
能关注一下同志癌吗?
Can you give to gay cancer?
有一场…我们社群正在经历一场危机
There's a... there's a crisis in our community right now.
我们真的用得到...
We could really use...
我们用得到你们的帮助 好吗? 不?
We could use a little help. Anything? No?
我觉得你可以少一点点进攻性
I think you could be a little less aggressive.
少一点进攻性? 我们试过了
Less aggressive? We've tried that.
能关注一下我们社群发生的癌症吗?
Can you give to cancer in our community?
嗨 关注同志癌吗?
Hi, give to gay cancer?
很可笑 我妈妈送了花来
It's funny. My mother sent flowers.
我甚至没跟她说过我是同志
And I had never told her I was gay.
我只跟她说克雷格死了
I just told her that Craig had died.
我觉得她知道
I think she knew.
我认为妈妈们总是能知道
I think somehow mothers always know.
在一套房子上面花5百万你不感到害怕吗?
Doesn't spending $5 million on a house frighten you?
光是让你来打理我的财务都让我心惊肉跳
Scared the shit out of me even having you handling my finances
你想要买房的话随时都可以
You can have a house anytime you want.
这提醒了我 你的帐户需要更多钱
Which reminds me, your account needs more money.
事实上你干得不赖
You're not doing too badly.
我怀念你投身电影业的日子
I miss you being in the movie business.
- 我喜欢电影 - 我嗅到被否定了吗
- I like movies. - Do I detect a note of approval
我的大哥刚管我从事的是”柠檬”? (次品的意思)
from the big brother that called me "Lemon"?
我不想购房
I don't want a house.
那你干嘛一直在郊区晃荡?
Then why have you been searching in the country for so long for?
- 一个人住不好玩 - 这个布鲁斯...
- No fun living in it alone. - This Bruce...
你在和他交往吗?
is he someone you're seeing?
我看得到他 他看不到我
I see him, he doesn't see me.
本…
Ben...
你的律所能免费接下这个吗
could your law firm take this on for free
怎么说 无偿代理?
What's it called? Pro bono?
我们成立了一个组织 我跟你说过有种新疾病…
We started an organization, I told you there's this new disease…
这听上去像又一个让你停止写作的借口
Now this sounds like just another excuse to keep from writing.
你为什么就不能直接说"好"?
Why can't you just say "yes"?
我跟你说了 因为我们有内部委员会来决定这类事情
I told you because we have a committee that decides that kind of thing
可你是高级合伙人
But you're the senior partner
而我是你弟弟
and I'm your brother.
嘿 马里奥 霍默还好吗?
Hey, Mario. How's Homer?
如果你不肯帮忙 我只能找其他人了
If you're not gonna help, I'm gonna have to find somebody else.
- 欢迎你找其他人 - 我不想找其他人
- Well, you're more than free to do that. - I don't want to do that
我想我大哥的气派 有名 一流 大型的律所
I want my big brother's fancy, famous, big-time, major law firm
成为纽约市第一家
to be the first straight New York law firm
无偿代理同志事业的直人律所
to do pro bono work for a gay cause.
我会为它 为你感到无比的骄傲
I'd be real proud of that and you
下一次会议我会让其他合伙人通过它
I'll ask my partners' approval at the next meeting.
我要去游说 你听上去不像会投赞成票的
I'll lobby them. You don't sound like a very sure vote.
好了
Okay.
你的反应有进步
You're getting better at it.
我每周都在增加3到4个新病人
I'm seeing three to four new patients a week.
7个进了重症监护室 整个医院只有30个床位
I've got seven in ICU. The whole hospital only has room for 30
他们当中有的人被检查出其他病
I've had to admit some of them under other illnesses
这是最糟的
That's a no-no.
有20个人住了承担不起的私人病房
I've got 20 in private rooms they can't afford.
那些没有医疗保险的人呢...
Okay, what about the guys who don't have health insurance...
- 艺术家 演员? - 他们中有8个住在另一间
- Artists, actors? - I've got eight of them in another ward
我不该安排他们住的病房
where I shouldn't put them.
你怎么不戴手套和面罩?
Why don't you wear gloves and a face mask?
我永远不戴 永远不打算戴
Never have and I never will.
结果我仍然在这儿
And I'm still here.
为什么所有食物都这样摆在病房外?
Why is all the food sitting outside their rooms like this?
- 它们会变冷 - 它们总是冷的
- It's getting cold. - It's always cold
因为当值的工作人员不肯送进房间
because the appropriate staff won't bring it into the rooms
所以食物就在外面发霉 直到我的人员经手
so it sits and rots until one of my staff can.
就在那儿 嗯 就在水边
Right there. Yeah, by the water.
嗯 通过隧道
Yeah, right through the tunnel.
通过隧道 把书放回去
Take the tunnel. We'll take the book back.
我认识他 我可以和你一起进去吗?
I know him. Can I go inside with you?
除非你穿上那些保护件
Only if you wear all the protective shit.
你不穿 我也不穿
If you don't, I don't.
就在那儿 换一条路
Over there. Go the other way.
不 听到我说的了吗?
No, are you listening to me?
听到我说的了吗 往回走
Are you listening to me? Go back.
- 嗨 桑福德 - 看到了吗 走隧道
- Hi, Sanford. - You see that? Take the tunnel.
往前开 穿过它
Go ahead, drive straight through.
你怎么样 士兵?
How we doing, soldier?
我想见我的狗 能带我的狗来吗?
I want my dog. Can you please bring me my dog?
没有我它没法生活
He won't be able to live without me.
我想见我的狗 我想见我的狗
I want my dog. I want my dog.
直走 没错
Go ahead. That's right.
很好 不 把书放回去
Oh, good. Good. No. Take the book back.
就在那儿 用力推
Right there. Pull hard.
就在那儿
Right there.
能把我的狗带来吗?
Can you please bring me my dog?
没有我它没法生活
He won't know how to live without me.
别管了
Don't bother.
谁会带我的狗来?
Who's going to bring me my dog?
它叫跳跳 你叫它它就会来
His name is Skip. He'll come when you call him.
求你了
Please.
我想它
I miss him.
我想它了
你19岁时能想象这些吗?
Can you imagine this at 19?
你的第一个男友 你打算和他厮守终生的
Your first boyfriend you were gonna spend your whole life with.
- 抱歉 - 嗯
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
你是修电视的?
You're the TV guy?
请去407室修一下电视
Please go to room 407 and fix it.
- 不 我拒绝进去 - 修电视 这是你他妈的工作
- No I'm not gonna do that. - Fix the TV. It's your fucking job
我的工会说 我不需要冒生命危险
My union says I don't gotta risk my life
去服务一些会传染的娘泡
for some contagious fairy.
如果非要我进去 我就他妈的不干了
If I have to go in there, then I fucking quit.
所以你的工会到底又在做什么?
So what exactly has your side been doing?
- 嗨 - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
谢谢
Thanks.
来点这个吗? 还是啤酒?
Want some of this? A beer?
噢 啤酒就可以 谢谢
Oh, beer's fine. Thanks.
嘿 狗狗
Oh, hey, pooch.
- 她叫珊姆 - 嗨 珊姆
- Her name's Sam. - Hi, Sam.
知道吗 我以前真的喜欢高科技装潢
You know, I really used to like high-tech
不过现在厌倦了
but I'm tired of it now.
我希望印花布能回归
I think I want chintz back again.
别觉得我说话冲了啊
Don't be insulted.
我不觉得
I'm not.
我也希望印花布能回归
I want chintz back again, too.
所以 我和你
So, here we are.
两个希望印花布回归的人
Two fellows who want chintz back again.
看来这真的是一个约会
I guess this really is a date.
我饿坏了
I'm starving.
- 你高兴我来吗? - 噢...
- You glad I'm here? - Oh...
你能来我高兴得不得了
I'm pleased as punch you're here.
你很帅气 你在干嘛?
You're very good-looking. What are you doing here?
你觉得自己丑吗?
You think you're bad-looking or something?
你是哪儿的人?
Where you from?
俄克拉荷马州
I'm from Oklahoma.
我18岁时离开家 自己供自己…
I left home at 18, put myself through...
怎么 你要跳舞吗?
what, you wanna dance?
自己供自己念了大学
Put myself through college.
我爸爸在西塔尔萨市的炼油厂上班
My dad worked at the refinery in West Tulsa
我妈妈是女招待
and my mom was a waitress.
在沃尔格林药店有一个快餐摊
Had a luncheonette in Walgreens.
很了不起 不是吗? 一个小鬼从这一切冒出来
It's amazing, isn't it? How a kid comes out of all that
最后走进"时报"
and wind up on the "Times"
指挥整个世界的品位与时尚
dictating taste and style to the entire world.
我们终于开始好好说话了
And we were just starting to talk so nicely.
说不是我的问题
Talking's not my problem.
闭嘴才是
Shutting up's my problem.
你干嘛写那些花哨舞裙玩意儿?
Why do you write all that fancy ball gown bullshit?
我敢说你每天都会盯着看
I bet you gobble it up every day.
我认识的人已经有10个死了
I know 10 people who have died.
在我去找你的时候 还只有1个
When I came to you, it was only one.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
所以你才同意这个约会的吗?
Is that why you agreed to this date?
叉在左边
Fork on the left.
刀在右边
Knife on the right.
知道希特勒灭绝犹太人的"最后解决方案"
Did you know that Hitler's Final Solution to eliminate the Polish Jews
第一次被"时报"提及是在哪儿吗? 第28版
was first mentioned in the "Times"? It was on page 28.
"华盛顿邮报" 第6版
On page 6 of the "Washington Post."
两家都是犹太人的报纸 自己人的
They are both owned by Jews. Their very own people.
学者们终于开始如实记叙了 每个人都被拷问
Scholars are finally writing honestly about it and it's damning to everyone
基督教会在哪儿? 教皇? 丘吉尔? 罗斯福?
Where is the Christian churches? The Pope? Churchill? Roosevelt?
他们当中任何人说些什么都会警告希特勒
A few words from any of them would have put Hitler on notice.
达豪集中营1933年开张的 所有人都他妈的在哪儿?
Dachau was open in 1933. Where the fuck was everybody?
这一晚看来会变得非常浪漫啊
This is turning out to be a very romantic evening.
你从没有过爱人 对吗?
You've never had a lover, have you?
看来你有过不少
I suppose you've had quite a few.
我有过一个很好的
I had a very good one.
在一起很多年 所以谢谢
For a number of years, thank you.
他比我大 找到了个更年轻的
He was older than I was and he found someone younger.
- 你是恋父吗? - 不 我没有恋父情结 上帝啊
- You looking for a father? - No, I'm not looking for a father. God.
你真的很残酷
You're relentless.
好吧
Okay.
这是你的
That's yours.
每个人都有无数理由不牵扯进来
Everybody had a million reasons for not getting involved
美国犹太人完全知道在发生什么
The American Jews knew exactly what was going on.
你能想象如果每个犹太人都骄傲的去华盛顿游行吗?
Could you imagine if every Jew had marched on Washington proudly?
内德
Ned.
你不记得我了 对吗?
You don't remember me, do you?
那是几年前 在浴室
It was at the baths a few years ago.
欢迎来男国 看看我们做什么
Come to Man's Country, see what we're all about
我们能提供什么
and what we have to offer.
男国是一家设施齐全 多层套式的浴室
Man's Country is a full facility, multileveled complex
为每个人个性化服务而设计的
that was designed to feature something for everyone.
可以来男国强健身体…
Come to Man's Country to develop your body...
或是与其他人发展友谊
or a friendship with somebody else's.
来过一次你就会再来的
Visit us once and you'll come again and again.
你看我的样子 就像我是在申请加入中情局
You thought I was applying for the CIA the way you looked at me
然后发生了什么?
And then what happened?
我跟着你走进你的房间
I followed you into your room.
你甚至没睁开你的眼睛
You couldn't even open your eyes.
你跟我说你的真名叫亚历山大
You told me your real name was Alexander.
我问你是做什么的 结果你说
I asked what you did and you said something like
你"做过各种事情" 然后…
you "tried a number of things" and...
我问有没有包括爱
I asked if that had included love.
就在那时你说 "我早上还要早起呢”
That's when you said, "I have to get up early in the morning."
没错
Yeah.
男人不是天生不去爱的
Men do not naturally not love.
他们只是学会了不去爱
They learn not to.
我觉得你在伪装自己
I think you're a bluffer.
我怎么会不记得你?
How could I not remember you?
我不知道
I don't know.
当时很黑
It was very dark.
你觉得我们可以重新开始吗?
Do you think we could start over?
嗯
Yeah.
我上耶鲁的时候 我以为我是那儿唯一的同志
When I was going to Yale, I thought I was the only gay guy there
我发誓
Swear to God.
我去看想改造我的心理医生
Went to the shrink who tried to change me.
结果有了"同志威克斯"
Now they have "Gay Weeks" there
他比那儿的任何人都会跳舞
and they throw the best dances of anyone.
想象一下如果能在最美好的大学时光
Imagine being able to dance cheek to cheek
和你的男友脸贴脸跳舞
with your boyfriend during your bright college days.
你有跟女人睡过吗?
Did you ever sleep with a woman?
怎么了?
What?
她叫...黛利拉
Her name was... Delilah.
黛利拉?
Delilah?
她是...
She was...
我写的一部电影的替身演员
a stand-in on this movie I wrote.
她人很好 很漂亮
She was very nice and pretty.
经常对我微笑
Always smiling at me.
所以… 我让一个直人朋友教了我一些
So I... I asked a straight friend to explain it to me.
我以为我知道 但我只想确认
I thought I knew, but I just wanted to make sure.
我请她共用晚餐…
And I had her to dinner and...
然后我觉得到合适时候了
afterwards, what I deemed to be a suitable moment
因为我一直在给下面做工作...
because I had been communicating with it down there...
"你准备好了吗? 你确定准备好了吗?"
"Are you ready? Are you absolutely certain you're ready?"
当我的"独角兽"像是准备好了
And when it appeared "Abercrombie" was ready.
我把她抱起来 非常白瑞德 ("乱世佳人"男主角)
I picked her up, very Rhett Butler
把她放在我的床上
and carried her to my bed.
- 然后就软了 - 噢!
- Where I couldn't get it up. - Oh!
- 可是... - 我能体会
- But... - I can certainly relate to that.
在半夜的时候 我醒过来
In the middle of the night, I woke up with this
胯下肿涨得惊人 天知道怎么回事
gigantic erection, God... God knows how.
我推醒她 大叫 "求你了 帮我把它塞进去 黛利拉"
So I shake her, shouting, "Please stick it in for me, Delilah."
我害怕它会在我找到...
I was afraid of it going away before I could...
能够放进去的合适地方前软了
while I was hunting for the right place to put it.
她做了 我做了 我的独角兽做了
She did and I did, and Abercrombie did.
第二天早上我醒来
The next morning I woke up
一直生活在那个下决心要改造我的
and I, who had been under the spell of this shrink
心理医生的魔咒里的我
who was determined to change me
冲进他的办公室
rushed into his office.
那个从7年级起一直干男人的我
And I, who had been fucking with fellows since the 7th grade
在32岁时歇斯底里的宣布
hysterically, at the age of 32 proclaimed
"吉里斯皮医生 我不再是处男了!”
"Dr. Gillespie, I'm no longer a virgin!"
他在这儿 我们应该能碰到他
He's in here. I think we'll catch him.
好了
All right.
所以我就走过去打招呼?
So, I just go over and say hello?
我跟他说我邀请了你 我们一起念的耶鲁
I told him I invited you and we went to Yale together.
反正是我的送行派对 他能把我怎样?
It's my farewell party. What's he gonna do?
走吧
Let's go.
市长希望您消失
His Honor would like you to get lost.
- 这是我的朋友 内德·威克斯 - 我们知道他是谁
- This is my friend, Ned Weeks. - Yeah, we know who he is
市长先生! 我们需要你的帮助!
Mr. Mayor! We need your help!
新的疾病正在流行 你一定听说了
There's this new disease. You must have heard about it.
我们亟需你的帮助! 放开我 混球些!
We need your help badly! Get off me, you pigs!
这里是美国!
This is America!
市长先生! 我们正在死去!
Mr. Mayor! We're dying!
好的 这是内德写给我们准备投递的
Okay, this is what Ned wrote for us to send out.
"我受够了人们哀号要放弃滥交…
"I am sick of guys moaning that giving up careless sex..."
这让他们比死还难受
"...until this blows over is worse than death.
我受够了人们只用阴茎来思考
I am sick of guys that can only think with their cocks.
我受够了深柜的同志 1982年了 伙计们
I am sick of closeted gays. It's 1982 now, guys
你们什么时候出柜? 到1983年你们可能已经死了"
when are you gonna come out? By 1983 you could be dead."
你疯了
You're crazy.
是吗 布鲁斯? 你真这么觉得?
Am I, Bruce? Do you really think so?
我们今晚不是该选出一个主席吗?
Aren't we supposed to elect a president tonight?
我们不能教人们怎么过他们的生活 内德
We can't tell people how to live their lives, Ned.
整个同志政治运动都是关于做爱
The entire gay political movement is fucking.
嗨
Hi.
我对为病人提供一些服务项目更感兴趣
I'm very interested in starting up some sort of services for the patients
我们该开始谈谈他们了
We've gotta start talking about them.
另外还有很多担惊受怕的人们
Also, there are a lot of very scared people out there
他们格外需要信息
and they're desperate for information.
我想开办一条热线
I'd like to start a hotline.
他是谁?
Who's he?
噢 他还不知道我是谁
Ooh, he does not know who I am yet.
他叫汤米·鲍特莱特
His name is Tommy Boatwright.
现实中他是一位医院主任
In real life, he is a hospital administrator.
他是来帮忙的 而且是个南方骚婆娘
He's here to help and he's a Southern bitch.
鲍特莱特先生 我是布鲁斯·奈尔斯
Mr. Boatwright, Bruce Niles.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我的荣幸
- Nice to meet you. - My pleasure.
你很帅
You're very handsome.
他知道
He knows.
这他妈是什么?
The fuck is this?
这是你的主意吗 内德?
Was this your idea, Ned?
我在看 但我看不到问题?
I'm looking. What am I not seeing?
- 继续看 - 我们附的回邮地址
- Keep looking. - What we put for our return address.
你是说就因为信封上有"同志"这个词吗?
Do you mean because the word "gay" is on the envelope?
正他妈是 为什么不只是我们的缩写
Fucking A, yes. Instead of just our initials.
- 我们不能投递这些 - 抱歉
- We can't send these out. - Excuse me.
如果我们希望有人来参加这个舞会
If we want anybody to show up for this dance
我们必须在今晚投递它们
we have to get these out tonight.
我们需要用荧光笔涂掉"同志"这个词
We need to go through and scratch out the word "gay" with a Magic Marker
亲爱的 涂一万次?
Oh, honey, 10,000 times?
布鲁斯 我同情那些仍然和父母
Bruce, I have sympathy for kids living at home on Long Island
居住在长岛的孩子 可是...
with their parents, but...
那些会收到这些信的人... 看看你
but the guys who are getting these... look at you.
你有家... 你一个人住 拥有自己的公寓
You live at home... you live alone, you own your own apartment
你妈妈住在另一个州
your mother lives in another state.
我的邮差知道了怎么办?
Okay, what about my mailman?
你不是要我觉得你是认真的吧
You don't expect me to take you seriously.
- 我是认真的 内德 - 好了 女士们 乖乖的
- Yes, I do, Ned. - Okay, ladies, behave.
好了 已经很晚了 我们仍然没有一个主席
Look, it's getting late and we still haven't elected a president
内迪…
Neddy...
我觉得应该是布鲁斯
I think that it should be Bruce.
每个人都认识他 每个人都喜欢他 每个人…
Everybody knows him everybody likes him and everybody…
因为他人缘好 而每个人都怕我?
'Cause he's popular and everybody's afraid of me?
是的!
Yes!
你看他嘛 他…帅呆了
I mean, look at him. He's... he's gorgeous
所有克里斯朵夫街和火烧岛的小鬼 (均为同性恋聚集地)
and all the kids in Christopher Street and Fire Island
他们感觉会更舒服 假如跟随他的话
they'll just... feel a little bit more comfortable following him
- 就跟高中一样 - 是的!
- Just like high school. - Yes!
好了 所有支持布鲁斯·奈尔斯
All right, all those in favor of Bruce Niles
成为我们主席的人 请举手
as our first president, raise their hands.
我不想要这个
I don't think I want this.
拜托 你帅呆了 我们都会跟随你
Oh, come on. You're gorgeous and we're all gonna follow you.
- 干你 我接受了 - 干你 恭喜了
- Fuck you, I accept. - Well, fuck you, congratulations.
菲尼克斯 让我们搬到很远
Felix... let's move somewhere far away
就我们俩 一起去一个无人的小岛
just the two of us, together on a desert island.
你不能停下一秒钟不去想事情吗
Don't you dare stop for one second what you're doing.
我很感激你没有吼我 关于"时报"的不作为
I appreciate you not yelling at me about what the "Times" isn't doing
还有我的不够政治性 你为什么没有?
And my not being more political. Why don't you?
不用和某个人谈政治其实是一种解脱
It's a relief not having to have to talk politics with someone
但这不是原因
but that's not the reason.
不是?
No?
因为你就像一个不真实的梦
It's because you're too good to be true
因为我这辈子都在等一个像你这样的爱人
because I've been waiting for a lover like you my whole life
直到你终于出现
you haven't showed up until now
我害怕自己做出什么蠢事把它搞砸害怕到死
and I'm scared shitless that I'm gonna do something to fuck it up
- 我是不是疯子? - 当然
- Am I crazy? - Of course.
所以我才在这儿
That's why I'm here.
现在我们暖和了
Now we gettin' warm.
我看着还好吗?
Did I look okay?
能看出我化了很厚的妆吗?
Could you tell I was wearing all this makeup?
你看着好极了
You looked great.
你必须去艾玛那儿看看
You have got to go see Emma.
我们能忘了这个吗?
Can we just forget about this?
我很好
I'm all right.
如果不好我也不想知道 因为没人会用我
And if I'm not, I don't wanna know because no one will hire me
而如果我不能工作 我还不如死了
If I can’t work I just assume I’m dead
我体重有下降吗?
Have I lost any weight?
我还能补回来
I can still cover it up.
- 我跟你说过别告诉他的 - 对不起
- I told you not to tell him. - Sorry.
已经害怕和我接吻了?
Already afraid to kiss me?
不是这样
That's not true.
没事 我还害怕过给你呢
It's okay. I'm afraid to let you.
我爱你
I love you.
我送他回去
I'll walk him down.
好吧 他是我交往的第三个男人
Okay, he's the third guy I've been with.
莱因哈特 克雷格 现在我不知道自己能做什么
Reinhardt, Craig, and I don't know what I'll do
假如埃尔伯特也得了
if Albert has this.
你得战斗
You're gonna fight.
我们一起战斗
We'll fight together.
你是我最好的朋友 内德·威克斯
You're my best friend, Ned Weeks.
你是我最好的朋友 我没见过其他像你这样的
You're my best friend and I've never met anyone like you before.
什么意思 像我这样的?
What do you mean, like me?
像你 就是...
Like you, meaning...
在我的老家 我是说...
where I'm from, I... I mean...
直到我参军我才见到活的犹太人
I didn't even see a Jew until I was in the Army
更别说一个...
let alone a man that was…
聪明
smart
风趣
funny
好看的男人了
decently good-looking.
我的朋友不再跟我玩
My friends stopped hanging out with me
因为他们说我让他们扫兴
because they say I depress them.
随便了
So be it.
而且你...
And you...
你不怎么像犹太人
you don't look that Jewish.
你也不怎么像同志
Well, you don't look gay
所以我们都可以作为白人蒙混过关
so I guess we can both pass for white people.
我爱埃尔伯特
I love Albert.
布鲁斯 看着我
Bruce, look at me.
我爱他
I love him.
埃尔伯特会没事的
Albert's gonna make it.
万一有事呢?
What if he doesn't?
我送你回家吧
Let's get you home.
- 我真是一团糟 - 嗯
- I'm a mess. - Yeah.
- 经典一刻啊 - 嗯
- Classy moment. - Yeah.
- 我没事 - 好的
- I'm all right. - Okay.
当我和你终于变得我想要这样的时候
When I finally get you where I want you
我已经不想要和你这样了
I don't want you anymore.
布鲁斯 我也恋爱了
Hey, Bruce, I'm in love too.
嘿
Hey.
见他的鬼!
Holy shit!
变装皇后坐镇
Queen control.
它想要的时候还真管用
Really works when it wants to.
嘿 菲尼克斯 这是迪克·伦巴多
Oh, hey, Felix. This is Dick Lombardo.
- 嗨 - 我们的董事会终于有了个
- Hi. - Finally got us someone on our board
不迷恋迪斯科的人了
who isn't a disco dummy.
也许今晚除外
Well... maybe tonight.
- 稍后见 - 很高兴认识你
- I'll see ya. - Nice to meet ya.
过来
Come on.
"I will survive" (Gloria Gaynor)
今晚我们非常开心有你们加入!
We are all so happy you joined us tonight!
我们证明我们不只是
We are proving that we are more than just
外貌 头脑 才华 和心灵
looks, brains, talent and heart.
我们募集到了本市任何一个同志组织都没有募集过的钱
Together we raised more than any gay group ever in this city
我想请他上来
And I wanna call over
内德·威克斯先生
Mr. Ned Weeks.
别害羞啊
Don't be shy.
我们做到了
We did it
现在我们要宣布募集到多少钱
We will now reveal just how much we raised together.
三 二 一…
In three, two, one...
五万三千块!
$53,000!
男同志健康危机组织 都上来
Gay Men's Health Crisis, come on up.
菲尼克斯 亲爱的 上来 请上来
Felix, honey, come on up, please. Come up.
我爱你
I love you.
让咱们跳吧!
Let's dance!
♪有一天他会来♪
♪Someday he'll come along♪
♪我爱的男人♪
♪ The man I love♪
♪他会高大又强壮♪
♪And he'll be big and strong♪
♪我爱的男人♪
♪The man I love♪
♪当他朝我走来♪
♪And when he comes my way♪
♪我会尽我的所能♪
♪ I'll do my best♪
♪只为让他留下来♪
♪To make him stay♪
♪他会看着我微笑♪
♪ He'll look at me and smile♪
♪我能理解♪
♪ I'll understand♪
♪就在一小会儿后♪
♪And in a little while♪
♪他会牵我的手♪
♪ He'll take my hand♪
♪尽管看上去可笑♪
♪And though it seems absurd♪
♪我知道我们都不会有片言♪
♪I know we both won't say a word♪
♪也许我该见他 在星期天♪
♪Maybe I shall meet him Sunday♪
♪也许在星期一♪
♪ Maybe Monday♪
♪也许不会♪
♪ Maybe not♪
♪我仍然确信要见他...♪
♪Still I'm sure to meet him...♪
想象如果我们年轻时就这样
Imagine if we had this when we were young.
没有恐惧 没有羞愧
No fear, no shame.
我会想象那些年都是和你在一起
All I was imagining all those years was you.
♪他会建造一个小小的家♪
♪ He'll build a little home♪
♪就住两个人♪
♪ Just meant for two♪
♪我永远也不再流浪♪
♪From which I'll never roam♪
♪是你 你会?♪
♪ Who would, would you?♪
♪所以重要过一切♪
♪And so all else above♪
♪我在等那个男人...♪
♪ I'm waiting for the man...♪
菲尼克斯·特勒 你愿意搬来和我同住吗?
Felix Turner, would you like to move in with me?
愿意
Yes.
- 真的? - 真的 就今天
- Yes? - Yes-terday
耶! 耶!
Yes? Yes!
♪所以重要过一切…♪
♪And so all else above...♪
♪我在等那个男人♪
♪I'm waiting for the man♪
♪我爱的男人♪
♪ I love.♪
我们都是活动的定时炸弹
We are all walking time bombs
等待着不管什么将我们引爆
waiting for whatever it is to set us off
我们就快到了
C'mon, we're almost there.
如果这篇文章还没把你吓得半死
If this article doesn't scare the shit out of you
男同志在地球上就没有明天了
Gay men may have no future here on Earth.
我们的存在取决于你们能有多么愤怒
Our continued existence depends on just how angry you can get.
他们拒绝给我们提供外籍急症室
They turned us away from foreign emergency rooms
快进来!
Come in!
我觉得他好像失去神智了
I think he's lost his mind.
内德 我要把他放哪儿?
D, where can I take him?
放在沙发上 我打给艾玛
Put him on the couch there. I'll call Emma.
- 妈的! - 我去倒水
- God damn it! - I'll get some water.
他这样多久了?
How long has he been like this?
几小时
A couple hours.
我很高兴你问了我这个问题
Well, I'm glad you asked me that question.
我怎么想? 我觉得政府
What do I think? I know that the government
在故意忽视这个流行病
is intentionally ignoring this epidemic.
你是在指控美利坚合众国政府
You're accusing the government of the United States
密谋杀害所有同性恋?
of a conspiracy to murder all gay men?
是的 是的 你可以这么说
Yes. Yes, you can say that.
没错 萨拉伯丝 我就是这意思 是的
Yes, Sarabeth, I am. Yes.
这是个很严重的指控啊
That is a powerful accusation.
现在有一场流行病
This is an epidemic
而它被美利坚合众国政府所忽视
and it's being ignored by the United States government.
- 故意的? - 故意的忽视
- Intentionally? - Intentionally being ignored.
这是国家紧急状态
This is a national emergency.
这是场大流行病 是一场瘟疫
This is an epidemic. It's a plague.
你不能在国家电视台指控政府谋杀 内德
You can't go on national TV accuse the government of murder, Ned
- 为什么不? - 因为有天我们会需要钱
- Why not? - Because one day we're gonna get money
研究 拨款
research grants.
国会仍然没有批准一分钱
Congress still hasn't appropriated a dime.
市长仍然置若罔闻
The mayor's still on and on!
内德 你在公开场合没有任何权利代言这家机构
Ned when you go public you have no right to speak for this organization
除非我们事先批准你要说什么
unless we have approved what you have to say in advance.
事实上 你甚至不是这个机构的管理层
In point of fact, you aren't even an officer of this organization
你完全不应该代言我们
and you shouldn't be speaking for us at all.
谢谢跟我分享这个 迪克 (有混球意思)
Well, thank you for sharing that with me, Dick.
交叉讨论
你觉得为什么这个城市这么迟缓
Why do you think the city has been so slow
承认和应对这个紧急状况?
to acknowledge and deal with this emergency?
你是在暗示这个城市已经承认
Well, you're implying that the city has recognized
这是一个紧急状况了 马尔科姆 它没有
and acknowledged this emergency, Malcolm. It has not.
你觉得为什么没有?
Why not, do you think?
因为市长是同志
Because the mayor's gay
他对自己的遮羞布被扯掉怕得要死
and he's scared shitless out of his panties it'll blow his cover
怎么了?
What?
- 关掉 关掉镜头 - 还在直播吗?
- Take it off, get it off. - Are we still rolling?
遭遇技术故障 请稍候
我只代言自己的时候 你不能决定我说什么
You can't tell me what to say when I'm speaking for myself
扯淡 大家都知道你是我们的一员
Bullshit. They all know you're one of us.
你这是完全的政治错误
It is totally and politically incorrect
你不能称呼某个没有宣布自己性向的人是同志
to call someone gay who does not self-identify as being gay
我知道应该是这样
I know it's been that way forever
但现在是特殊情况 我们正在死掉
but something different is going on here now. We're dying.
市长 他是你的私人朋友
The mayor, he's a personal friend of yours.
你希望他任命你当法官
You want him to appoint you a judge.
你不觉得这里存在一点利益冲突吗?
Do you have a little conflict of interest going on here?
- 我跟你说过我把备忘录发他了 - 什么时候?
- I told you I sent him a memo. - When?
- 透过我的关系 - 什么时候?
- Through channels. - When?
- 他会回答我 - 什么时候?!
- He'll answer me. - When?!
这个月新增了110个病例!
There's 110 new cases this month!
我们仍然不能和我们的同志市长会面
Still no meeting with our gay mayor.
不能和他的同志助理会面
No meeting with his gay assistant.
怎么 我给你难堪了吗 布鲁斯?
What? Do I embarrass you, Bruce?
是的 你给了
Yes. You do.
胡萝卜比大棒有更好效果 宝贝
You get more with honey than with vinegar, babe.
上帝 没人这么教过我 汤米
God, no one's told me that one, Tommy.
显然他们没有
No, obviously, they haven't.
不过我也不怎么信这套鬼话
I never believed that bullshit, anyway.
我们现在全部在做的是试着帮我们的病人
We are in over our heads with the patients we're trying to help
汤米 请你大声跟内德念一下这份报告好吗?
Tommy, will you please read this report out loud for Ned?
我们训练了25位危机辅导员
We have trained 25 crisis counselors
帮助新确诊的病人获得任何可能需要的帮助
to help the newly diagnosed in whatever needs that they might have
我们有12位团队领袖 和这些辅导员
We have 12 group leaders who meet with these counselors
每周至少见一次面 查看他们的病人情况
at least once a week to go over their clients.
现在有17位志愿社工
There are now 17 volunteer social workers
心理学家和(或)心理医生
psychologists and/or psychiatrists.
我们已经帮助起草了75份遗嘱...
We helped draw up 75 wills last...
75 布鲁斯!
75, Bruce!
你以前曾经是战士
You used to be a fighter once.
- 你喜欢在特种部队的日子吗? - 是的 我喜欢
- Did you like being in the Green Berets? - Yes. I loved it
你已经完全忘记怎么去战斗了吗?
Have you completely forgotten how to fight?
别跟我说怎么去战斗 我只是和你的战斗方式不同
Don't tell me how to fight. I just fight differently than you.
- 我没有看到你的方式 - 没有吗?
- I haven't seen your way yet. - No?
布鲁斯...埃尔伯特就要死了
Bruce... Albert may be dying.
你这混球! 你敢再说他一个字!
You son of a bitch! You say another word about him!
冷静
Relax.
还有你
And you.
你完全没有资格进这个董事会
You have no right being on this board
除非你给你的市长朋友施加压力
unless you put pressure on your friend the mayor.
这就是为什么我最开始邀你加入的原因 你自己知道
That's why I asked you to join us in the first place and you know it
- 不 我不做 - 为什么不?
- No, no, I'm not gonna do that. - Why not?
你已经从我的律所得到免费法律服务了
No, you got your free legal work from my firm.
我才不要进你的董事会
I'm not gonna be on your board of directors.
只是象征意义的 你不需要做一件事
It's only for the stationery. You don't have to do a thing.
你这是在逃避 如果它是个直人病...
That is just an evasion. If you thought this was a straight disease...
这和你是同志没有关系
It's got nothing to do with you being gay.
那它还和什么有关系?
What else does it have to do with?
迟早有一天 我会让你认同
One of these days, I'm gonna get you to agree
这个国家超过两千万的男女同性恋
that over 20 million men and women in this country
不需要去接受心理医生辅导
don't require the services of a psychiatrist.
试着理解我一下
Look, try to understand.
我有看报 看电视
You know, I read stuff, I see TV.
那些男的穿皮革 链子
Guys in leather and chains.
裙子 高跟鞋
Dresses, high heels.
我跟自己说 "内德不是这样的”
I say to myself, "This isn't Ned."
你知道媒体总是极端戏剧化一切
You know the media always dramatizes the most extreme.
你们有非常糟糕的形象问题
You guys have a dreadful image problem.
所以你这样的人支持我们才这么重要
That's why it's so important to have people like you supporting us
你已经有你的威望了
You already have your dignity.
我们最好现在就吃午饭 我有个重要会议
We better get to lunch. I've got an important meeting.
你有吗? 多重要?
Do you? How important?
我在请求你的支持
I'm asking for your support.
在所有我觉得重要的事上 你都得到我的支持
In every area I consider important, you have my support.
而在我唯一觉得重要的事上
The only area that I consider important
我完全没有你的支持
I don't have your support at all.
在你内心深处某个地方
In some place deep down inside you
你还是觉得我有病 对吗?
you still think I'm sick, don't you?
我觉得你很好适应了生活
I think you've adjusted to life pretty well.
- 难怪了 - 我看过你有多么不开心
- All things considered. - I saw how unhappy you were.
你也一样!
So were you!
你也不得不看心理医生 我们并肩成长起来的
You wound up going to shrinks, too. We grew up side by side.
我们对爸爸和妈妈都有同样体会
We both felt the same about Mom and Pop.
我承认我有一大堆可怕的性格缺陷
I agree to the fact that I have any number of awful character traits
但我不承认是他们对我们做过的可怕事情
but not to the fact that whatever awful things they did to us
让我生病和变同性恋 而你依然健康和异性恋的
made me sick and gay while you stayed straight and healthy.
我们对一些事情的反应不一样
We don't all react the same way to the thing.
所以你成了律师 我成了作家
So you became a lawyer and I became a writer.
我们有不同的理论分歧
Well, we have a difference of opinion over theory.
可是你的理论把我看成一个火星来客
But your theory turns me into a man from Mars.
我的理论不这么看你
My theory doesn't do that to you.
我是在暗示我做错了
Are you suggesting I did something wrong
不该在你那么小就送你去看医生吗?
in sending you into therapy so young?
我不知道你会永远留在那儿
I didn't know you were gonna stay there forever.
我根本没觉得自己做错了什么
I didn't think that I'd had done anything wrong
直到你送我去那儿
until you sent me there.
本 你对我来说比世界上任何人都重要
Ben... you mean more to me than anyone in the whole world
- 一直如此 本 你得说出来 - 说什么?
- You always have. Ben, you gotta say it. - Say what?
我和你一样 说出来 说啊!
I'm the same as you. Just say it. Say it!
不
No.
你不是
You're not.
我不会说
I'm not gonna say it.
每次输掉这场争论 都让我更受伤
Every time I lose this fight, it hurts more.
- 我回家了 - 别这样 柠檬
- I'm going home. - Oh, come on, Lemon.
我依然爱你
I still love you.
莎拉依然爱你
Sarah still loves you.
- 我们的猫依然爱你 - 这不是一个玩笑
- The cat still loves you. - This is not a joke.
你有我的爱 我的法律服务 我的财务监督
You have my love, my legal advice, my financial supervision
我没法给你站在我面前
I can't give you the courage to stand up to me
说你根本他妈不在乎我是怎么想的勇气
and say you don't give a flying fuck about what I think.
每个人都会在别人那儿受挫
Everybody's oppressed by somebody else
不管是哪种形式的
in some form or another.
我们中大多数人学会怎么克服它 不管别人怎么想
Most of us learn to fight against it despite people's opinions
不管有没有别人的帮助
without the help of others.
停止再从我这儿撩起什么负罪感
And stop trying to wring some kind of admission of guilt out of me
要我认同你生下来就和我一样
Agreeing that you were born just the same as I was born
救不了你快死的朋友
isn't gonna save your dying friends.
这恰恰是能救我快死的朋友的东西
That is exactly what is going to save my dying friends.
- 你的口气就像我是你的敌人 - 我开始觉得
- You make it sound like I'm the enemy. - I am beginning to think
你和你的直人世界才是我们的敌人
that you and your straight world are our enemy.
我对你出离愤怒!
I am furious with you!
还有所有让我觉得爱上男人是病的该死的医生
And every goddamn doctor who made me feel it was sick to love a man
我在试着理解
I am trying to understand
为什么没人他妈的在乎我们正在死去!
why nobody gives a shit that we're dying!
一个五百万的房子? 我们甚至从市政府领不到27分钱
$5 million for a house? We can't even get 27 cents from the city.
我认识的人有43个死了 你说这是我的事业不是你的?
I know 43 guys who have died and you say it's my cause not yours?
你仍然觉得我有病
You still think I'm sick
我再也没办法忍受一分一秒
I simply cannot allow it for one single second longer.
我不会再和你讲话 直到你接受我作为和你一样的对等!
I will not speak to you again until you accept me as your equal!
一样健康的对等!
Your healthy equal!
你的弟弟!
Your brother!
小心点 男孩们
Yeah, be careful with that, boys.
- 那是珍贵古董 - 放松
- That is a precious antique. - Easy.
我在想我们是不是该把它放进沙龙间
I'm thinking we should put that in the grand salon.
我们有地下室吗? 我觉得它该去那儿
Do we have a basement? That's where it should go.
贝拉 我觉得是时候让你的臭嘴见天日了
Bella, I think it's time we moved your filthy mouth above ground.
我明天再来收拾
I'll decorate tomorrow.
你们先尽可能把它摁进去
Just shove it all in there the best you can.
噢
Oh.
好了 别闹了 你们两个
Okay, knock it off, both of you.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 噢 嗨 - 嗨
- Yes, hi. - Hi.
我叫埃斯特拉
My name is Estelle
我最好的朋友哈维昨晚死了
and my best friend Harvey died last night.
我们去哪儿都在一起 知道吗
We went everywhere together, you know
比如去百老汇 看火箭女郎歌舞
Like Broadway and the Rockettes
溜冰
and ice skating.
他溜得好极了
He was a beautiful skater.
我很笨
I'm a klutz.
可他不在意
But he didn't care.
我们曾经那么的开心
We had so much fun.
妈的 我想做点什么!
Damn it, I wanna do something!
哪怕我所有拉拉朋友都说
Even though all my lesbian friends say
“你们又为我们做过什么?”
"What have you guys ever done for us?"
可是我不管
But I don't care.
就当这是为了哈维
This is for Harvey.
求你了 告诉我可以用到我什么
Please... tell me you can use me for something.
我需要一个热线主管 你觉得可以做吗?
I need a hotline director. You think you can do that?
- 我不知道怎么做 - 我也一样
- I don't know how. - I don't either.
嘿
Hey.
让我给你买杯咖啡
Let me buy you a cup of coffee
- 然后我们再想办法 好吗? - 好
- and we'll figure this out, okay? - Okay.
- 所以你想架在这儿? - 是的 这儿很好 我们拍吧
- So, you want to set up here? - Yeah, this is good. Let's do it.
- 你们在干嘛? - 我们是NBC下属台的
- What are you doing? - We're from the NBC affiliate.
- 所以? - 这里是新的男同健康危机办公室吗?
- So? - This is the new Gay Men's Health Crisis office?
- 你是谁? - 我是布鲁斯·奈尔斯 我是主席
- Who are you? - I'm Bruce Niles. I'm the president.
我没有签署任何允许拍我或这家机构的同意书
I didn't sign any consent form for you to film me or this establishment
- 请立刻关掉镜头 - 别碰我的摄像机
- Please turn it off and leave. - Hey, now, don't touch my camera.
- 谁派你来的? - 一个叫内德的
- Who sent you here? - Somebody named Ned.
- 威克斯 - 噢 太好了 你们来了
- Weeks. - Oh, great. You're here.
这里有基佬吗?
Anybody homo?
混球
Son of a bitch.
镜头在拍吗?
Hello, is this thing rolling?
快看 同一周的两本杂志都有我们
Look at this. We're in both of them the same week.
每家主流电视网络
Every major network
现在终于有第一间我们的办公室了
and now finally our very first office.
我给你们介绍我们还在柜子里的同志主席
I wanna introduce you to our gay president who's in the closet.
他是那么帅气 你们不觉得吗?
And he's so handsome. Don't ya think?
这么帅气的封面男孩浪费了多可惜
Such a very handsome cover boy going to waste.
太好了 现在你要战斗了 战斗啊 布鲁斯
Oh, great. Now you fight. Great. Fight, Bruce.
你把我说得像个懦夫 我不是懦夫
You made me sound like a coward and I'm not a coward.
知道吗? 你没有什么可失去的
You know what? You have nothing to lose.
你哥哥替你投资 所以你有收入
Your brother invests for you so you have income.
你可以一天24小时当同志 内德 可是我不行!
You can be gay 24/7, Ned, but I can't!
我不行! 所以去你妈的!
I can't! So fuck you!
不 去你妈的 布鲁斯!
No, fuck you, Bruce!
上帝啊
Jesus.
当我看着你 我充满了失望
When I look at you, I am filled with despair.
当我看着你 我担心我们不可能赢
When I look at you, I worry we're not gonna win.
你觉得这个国家是建立在什么上?
How do you think this country was founded?
我以为它是从保罗·列维尔开始的 (警告美国人民反抗英军的报信人)
I thought I was getting started with Paul Revere
不是什么懦夫
not some coward.
内德 看着我 看着我!
Ned, look at me. Look at me!
看着我!
Look at me!
如果照你的方式 我们就完了
We are doomed if we do it your way.
- 完了! - 怎么要人们帮我们
- Doomed! - How are they going to help us
假如他们不知道我们是谁?
if they don't know who we are?
知道了我们是谁 他们就不会帮我们 内德
They won't help us, Ned, if they do.
嘿嘿 别这样
Hey, hey, hey! Hey! Come on.
- 见鬼 - 见鬼!
- Holy shit. - Shit!
我来接好了
Okay, I'll get it, sure.
喂? 你是我们接的第一个热线电话
Hello? Yeah, you are our very first call.
能为你做什么?
How can I help you?
抱歉 你打错了
I'm sorry, you have the wrong number.
你们现在就需要好好拾掇一下 知道吗?
You each gotta pull your shit together now, okay?
还有你需要停止做个抓马女王 烦死了
And you need to stop being such a fucking drama queen. God damn.
这是埃斯特拉
This is Estelle.
嘿 还好吗?
Hey. How's it going?
欢迎
Welcome.
“More than this” (Roxy Music)
反正我们有四只手 两份收入
Well, we have four hands and two incomes.
你也不会再变年轻
You're not getting any younger, you know.
别扯上我的年纪
All right, let's leave my age out of this.
- 郊区很美 - 郊区很安静
- Very beautiful, the country. - Very quiet, the country.
不不 你敢接
No, no. Don't you dare
我必须接
I have to.
别说你在答录机上留了这里的号码
You didn't leave this number on your machine.
- 你保证过 - 喂?
- You promised. - Hello?
我确实觉得我们该针对市长
I do think we should picket the mayor.
是的 我说的 而且我坚持原话 谢谢
Yes, I said that and I stand by that. Thank you.
你保证过
You promised.
不不不 等着
No, no, no, no, no. Wait.
任何男同志如果不站出来
And every gay man who is unable to come forward
和为挽救自己的生命而战斗
and fight to save his own life
事实上都在帮助杀害剩下的我们
is truly helping to kill the rest of us.
我们还要死多少人才能让你吓到半死
How many of us have to die before you get scared off your ass
做点什么? 谢谢
and into action? Thank you.
是谁啊?
Who was that?
听说它们叫”承受内德愤怒的学校”
I hear it's being called the "Ned Weeks School of Outrage."
我和我们一个科学报道的记者谈过了
I did speak to one of our science reporters.
他怎么说?
What did he say?
结果他是同志 他不肯...
It turns out he's gay and he won't...
千万别吼我
don't yell at me.
那些心理医生 他们也不是一无是处
All those shrinks, they must have done something right
瑞特沃医生
Dr. Ritvo,
- 马勒夫医生 - 马勒夫啊
- Dr. Malev, - Malev.
吉勒斯皮医生
Dr. Gillespie,
帕蒂医生
Dr. Patty
迈克辛医生 拉弗恩医生
Dr. Maxene, Dr. LaVerne.
为什么要我说这么久?
Why does that have to take so long?
谁让你只知道吃甜品
All you ever eat is desserts.
糖是生活中最重要的
Sugar's the most important thing in life.
其他一切只是存活
All the rest is just to stay alive.
该死
Shit.
- 怎么了? - 该死的董事会
- What? - The fucking board.
他们说我在制造恐慌 自己想出风头
They say I'm causing a panic, that I'm making myself a celebrity
他们没人愿意接受采访或上电视
Not one of them will be interviewed or appear on TV
所以我才自动接手
so I do it all by default.
所以你成为了领袖
And you're becoming a leader.
- 而你是好斗的 - 我好斗? 我吗?
- And you love to fight. - I like to fight? Moi?
你? 正是啊
Who, you? Yeah.
而且你乐在其中
And you're havin' a great time.
是的
I am.
很讽刺 我从没想过当一个领袖
It's funny, I never wanted to be a leader.
我做得不怎么好
I'm not doing very well.
可惜我们失去了那么多时间
It's sad how much time we lost.
我们那时还没准备好
We just weren't ready then.
假如我染上了...
If I had it...
你会离开我吗?
would you leave me?
我不知道
I don't know.
换作是我 你会吗?
Would you if I did?
不会
No.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
因为我母亲是地方红十字会的会长
Because my mother ran the local chapter of the Red Cross.
从我8岁起她就让我在采血车上工作
She put me to work in the Bloodmobile when I was eight.
我天生适合做这个
I'm not programmed for anything else.
内德 有件事我得告诉你
Ned, I have something to tell you.
你终于怀上了
You're finally pregnant.
我结过一次婚
I was married once.
你没跟我说过
You never told me that.
是的 我...
Yeah, I...
她说我对她不公平
she said I had been unfair to her
那时确实是
which I had been.
- 我有一个儿子 - 你有一个儿子
- I have a son. - You have a son.
- 她不让我见他 - 你不能见自己的儿子?
- She won't let me see him. - You can't see your own son?
你有反抗吗?
But didn't you fight?
那说明你感到羞愧
That means you're ashamed.
他迟早也会
So he will be, too.
这就是我不告诉你的原因 谁说我没反抗?
This is why I didn't tell you. Who says I didn't fight?
内德?
Ned?
如果别人没有你希望的那么坚强怎么办?
What happens to people who can't be as strong as you want them to be?
软弱能吓得我屁滚尿流!
Weakness scares the shit out of me!
我父亲就软弱 我害怕自己变成他
My father was weak, and I'm afraid I'll be like him.
他这辈子什么也不是 然后就结束了
His life didn't stand for anything and then it was over.
所以我不停战斗
So I fight, constantly.
我不明白如果我做得到
And if I can do it, I can't understand
为什么别人就做不到 好吗?
why everybody else can't do it, too, okay?
等等 你去哪儿?
Wait, where are you going?
菲尼克斯 你去哪儿?
Felix! Where you going?
菲尼克斯 我不是有意的 菲尼克斯
Felix. I didn't mean anything by that, Felix.
我...我害怕...很多事情
I... I... I'm scared of... lots of things.
真的 我恐高 我从没跟你说我害怕...
Really. Heights. I never told you I'm terrified of...
怎么了?
what?
它在越变越大
It keeps getting bigger and bigger.
不肯消失
It doesn't go away.
菲尼克斯?
Felix?
我能问谁是菲尼克斯吗?
Who, may I ask, is Felix?
我这辈子从没这样深的爱过
I've never been so in love in my life.
从没这样爱过
Never been in love in my life.
跟他说明早7点半来我那里
Tell him to come to see me first thing tomorrow 7:30.
内德 他妈的
Ned, God damn it.
我们能怎么办? 再也不和人相爱吗?
What are we supposed to do? Not be with anybody ever?
不是你以为的那么简单
It's not as easy as you might think.
艾玛 对不起
Oh, Em, I'm sorry.
没必要
Don't be.
你怎么瘫痪的?
How'd you get it?
我5岁的时候
I was five years old.
一个巴哈马岛的女人来到我们镇
A woman from the Bahamas came to our town
携带了小儿麻痹症病毒
carrying the polio virus.
她住在…一个朋友家
She... stayed with friends.
她的小孩和我幼儿园同班
Their kid was in my kindergarten class.
班上有4个孩子感染了
Four of us in that class got polio.
那天我穿着万圣节装扮
I was all dressed up in my Halloween costume
去玩"不给糖就捣蛋"游戏
to go trick-or-treating
妈妈摸了摸我的额头 把我放在床上
and my mother felt my forehead, put me to bed.
半夜的时候 我意识到除了胳膊和双手
In the middle of the night, I realized my whole body
我的全身都动不了了
except my arms and my hands were paralyzed.
我哭着叫我的妈妈
I was crying out for my mother.
"我不能动了 我不能动了"
"I can't move, I can't move."
他们把我送到医院
They rushed me to the hospital,
据说我活不过24小时
were told I'd be dead in 24 hours.
我战斗 活了下来
I fought. I lived.
你有上铁肺? (人工协助呼吸舱)
Were you in an iron lung?
有
I was.
然后我回到家的床上
Then I was in bed at home.
我和班上同学 靠一个小小的...
I was connected to my class with this little...
扩音器联系
Little loudspeaker.
所有的小孩被要求探望我
All the children were required to visit me.
我会在说 "嗨"
We would say, "Hello,"
然后就不知道说什么了
and then not know what to say next.
他们都害怕我了
They were all terrified of me.
现在还是如此
Still are.
我让人们怕得要死
I scare the shit out of people.
一个坐轮椅的"女魔头"
The "holy terror" in a wheelchair.
我也让人害怕
I'm scaring people, too.
学会好好利用它
Learn how to use it.
你不需要所有人的爱和认同
Don't need everybody's love and approval.
内德 你的机构…毫无用处
Ned, your organization is... worthless.
我没法得到董事会重量人物的支持
I can't get anyone important on the board.
我看过了300个病人 我 1个医生
I've seen over 300 patients. Me. One doctor.
那些从我们那儿赚走无数钱的人…
All these guys who made millions off of us...
时尚 摇滚 电影 房地产 都别指望了
fashion, rock, movies, real estate, forget it.
任何时候只要布鲁斯和我有异议
And any time Bruce doesn't agree with me
- 他就提请董事会表决  - 而你就输掉
- he puts it to a board vote. - And you lose.
我没法通过做爱建议
I can't pass along sex recommendations
或任何只要不是百分百确定的信息
or any information that isn't 100% certain.
科学上根本没有百分百的确定
Nothing is 100% certain in science.
你可以随便怎么说都行
It wouldn't matter what you say anyway.
别吼我说我什么也没做
Don't yell at me for what I'm not doing.
- 你那边又他妈的做了什么? - 我不知道!
- What the fuck is your side doing? - I don't know!
你的全美医学会呢?
Where's your A.M.A.?
作为犹太人 你是不是总感到饥饿?
Does being Jewish always make you hungry?
我不知道 我不是犹太人
I don't know. I'm not Jewish.
我是德国人
I'm German.
- 大家都以为你是犹太人 - 我知道
- Everybody thinks you're Jewish. - I know.
在医学界吃得开
In medicine it helps.
所以整个念书期间你都在床上度过的?
You stayed in bed the whole way through school?
上大学之前我戴上了第一套脚架
By college I had my first braces
我能...走一点点
and I could walk... a little.
现在不怎么能走了
I don't walk so good anymore.
也许是因为我没时间去练习
Probably because I'm too busy to practice.
你必须练习
You must practice.
就现在 我认真的
Right now. I mean it.
现在 来吧
Right now. C'mon.
别弄坏了我的马蒂斯唱片 (美国歌王)
Don't scratch my Mathis.
能邀您跳这支舞吗
May I have this dance
好吧 你自找的
Okay. You asked for it.
我的拐杖
My crutches.
♪在看见你的一刻 ♪
♪ The moment you come into view ♪
♪ 也许你觉得 ♪
♪ Chances are you think♪
"Chances Are" (Johnny Mathis)
我自己能行
Mm-mm. I got it.
- 噢... - 没事吧?
- Oh... - Okay?
没事
Okay. Mm-hmm.
我害怕留下他一个人
I'm afraid to leave him alone now.
我害怕解药不能及时到来
I'm afraid a cure won't come in time.
我害怕我的愤怒
I'm afraid of my anger.
- 我是个糟糕的领袖... - 还是糟糕的舞者 把我放回去
- I'm a terrible leader and... - A lousy dancer. Put me back.
小儿麻痹症也是种病毒
Polio is a virus, too.
现在没人得小儿麻痹症了
Nobody gets polio anymore.
他在哪儿? 我们在这儿一个半小时了
Where is he? We've been here for an hour and a half.
这些人是谁? 我们就像在他妈的地窖
Who are these people? We're in a fucking dungeon here.
他不能这样对我们 他不能这样对我们后还逍遥法外
He can't do this to us. He cannot do this to us and get away with it.
- 你们开始了吗? - 没有
- Did you start? - No.
- 幸好 嗨 - 嗨
- Okay, God, hi. - Hi.
老天爷 简直是坟墓
Jesus Christ, what a tomb.
他们不想在地表看到我们吗?
Do they not want us to be seen above ground?
他在哪儿? 我都是迟到一小时了
And where is he? I'm an hour late.
- 一个半小时 - 别找我的茬 坏家伙
- Ned: Hour and a half. - Don't start on me, lamb chop.
- 汤米 你在哪儿? - 我去贝尔维尤市了 (华盛顿州城市)
- Tommy, where were you? - I was up at Bellevue.
让一个快要死的可怜孩子和他的妈妈团聚
Had to put a sweet dying child together with his mama.
他们有15年没见了
They hadn't seen each other for 15 years.
他从没告诉她自己是同志
He never told her he was gay.
他不想见她 好几周都不让她过来
He didn't want to see her. He refused to see her for weeks.
我和他妈妈进去的时候他很生气
Oh, he was angry when I waltzed in with her.
太让人伤心了 当妈妈搂着她儿子
It was a real weeper. Mama holding her son.
他现在已经死了
He's dead now.
真对不起迟到了 我是希拉姆·吉布勒
I'm truly sorry I'm late. I'm Hiram Keebler.
你好 请问你在饼干业有亲戚吗? (吉布勒是美国第二大饼干制造商)
Hello. Are you related to the folks who make the crackers?
我开玩笑的 我是汤米·波特赖特
I'm kidding. I'm Tommy Boatwright.
内德·维克斯
Ned Weeks.
布鲁斯·奈尔斯 我是主席
Bruce Niles. I'm the president.
市长想让你们知道他有多重视
The mayor wants you to know how much he cares
对你们肯担起自己的责任 有多么的刮目相看
how impressed he’s with how you've been shouldering your own responsibilities
- 谢谢 - 谢谢?
- Thank you. - Thank you?
责任? 我们做的一切
Responsibilities? Everything we're doing
都是你们该做的 现在我们需要帮助
is the stuff you guys should be doing and we need help.
呃 维克斯先生其实想说的是
Uh, what Mr. Weeks is trying to say, sir
我们快超负荷了
is that... we're swamped.
我们每天要接500通热线电话
We're fielding over 500 calls a day on our emergency hotline.
我们提供的信息 说实话
And we're providing information that, quite frankly
应该是由市政府提供却没有的
the city should be providing, and isn't.
先生 我们需要办公场所 我们只有一个小间
Sir, we need office space. We have one small room.
每天有超过100人打电话来或进进出出
We have over 100 people calling or walking in and out every day
加上别人不肯租房子给我们 真的很棘手
and plus it's real hard when people don't want to rent to us
- 因为... - 哇噢 这是非法歧视啊
because we're... - Whoa. That's illegal discrimination.
是的 我们身受其害 先生
Yeah, we know that to be true, sir.
吉布勒先生 歧视同性恋不算非法呢
Mr. Keebler, it is not illegal to discriminate against homosexuals.
我们等待见市长已经等了14个月
We've been waiting for 14 months to see the mayor.
花了一年时间才能和你见面
It's taken us a year to get this meeting with you.
而你迟到了一个半小时
You're an hour and a half late.
你有告诉市长一场流行病正在爆发吗?
Have you told the mayor there's an epidemic going on?
- 谁说的? - 政府
- Uh, says who? - The government.
哪个政府? 我们的政府?
Which government? What? Our government?
- 流行病? - 全国疾控中心宣布...
- An epidemic? - The Centers for Disease Control declared it...
- 17个月前了 - 你不可能不知道!
- 17 months ago. - You can't not know this!
请控制一下你的歇斯底里等级吗?
Could you please reduce your level of hysteria?
当然
Certainly.
纽约 旧金山 洛杉矶
New York City, San Francisco, Los Angeles,
芝加哥 波士顿 丹佛 美国每一个主要城市
Chicago, Boston, Denver. Every single major American city
都出现了病例
is now showing cases.
还有至少25个海外国家 可纽约市
At least 25 foreign countries. But New York City
我们的家 你们宣称要保护的城市
our home, the city that you have pledged to protect
占了大半数据
has more than half of everything.
大半发病率 大半死亡人数
Half the cases, half the dead.
57个我知道的已经死了 我不想再听到更多
I know 57 of the dead ones. I don't wanna know any more.
那么 我们什么时候能见市长?
Now, when do we get to see the mayor?
出去吃14个月的午饭已经够长了
14 months is a long time to be out to lunch.
- 你等一等 - 不 你可以等 我们不能
- You wait a minute. - No, you wait a minute. We can't.
时间不站在我们这边
Time is not on our side.
如果你不肯向市长传话 我们能怎么办?
Now, if you won't take word to the mayor, what are we gonna do?
买一个精壮男妓送到市长官邸
Hire a hunky hustler and send him up to Gracie Mansion
在阴茎上刺上请愿的刺青吗?
with a plea tattooed to his cock?
- 科奇市长不是同志! - 得了吧 "布兰奇" ("欲望号街车"女主角)
- Mayor Koch is not gay! - Oh, come on, "Blanche."
听着
Listen.
你们觉得我不想帮你们?
Don't you think I want to help you?
我有朋友正因为这鬼病而死去
I have a friend who is dying of this shit
此时此刻 就躺在医院里
right now in the V.A. hospital.
但情况很微妙 你们看到了 情况很微妙
But it's very tricky. You can see that. It is very tricky.
微妙什么! 纽约有一百万同志
Tricky, shit! There are a million gay people in New York.
加上你就是一百万零一个!
A million and one counting you!
知道吗? 西区一所学校的暖气炉着火了
You know what? A fire goes out in a school furnace
我一天就接到了3000个电话
on the West Side. I get 3,000 calls in one day.
懂我的意思吧?
You know what I mean?
如果你们有很多人都很愤懑 为什么只有这个大嘴巴在滔滔不绝?
If so many of you are so upset, why do I only hear from this loudmouth?
- 这是个非常好的问题 - 好吧 假设本市有50万男同志
- That's a very good question. - Okay, so there are half a million
315个病人的比例也不算太高
gay men in our area. 315 cases doesn't seem too high
相较于我们...你们的总人数
considering how many of us... of you there are.
- 这是鬼扯! - 内德 求你了
- This is bullshit! - Ned, please.
我知道情况很微妙 先生
Look, I understand this is tricky, sir.
- 但我们需要你的帮助 - 我认为 市长也认为
- But we need your help - I think, that is, that the mayor thinks
你们反应过度了
you guys are overreacting.
你跟那个吸鸡巴的说 他是个自私的 冷血的狗娘养的!
You tell that cocksucker he is a selfish, heartless son of a bitch!
你是迈克尔·马科斯
You are Michael R. Marcus.
你在市卫生署的职位就快要不保了
You hold an unsecure job with the city's Department of Health.
我要是你 就会管住你的朋友
I'd watch out for your friends if I were you.
我不敢相信刚才发生了什么
I don't believe that just happened.
米奇 我明天就上"今日秀"
Mickey, I am going on "The Today Show" tomorrow
我要告诉所有人
and I am telling them
市长用你的饭碗作要挟 要我们闭嘴
that the mayor just threatened your job to shut us up.
"今日秀"? 你要做什么?
"The Today Show"? You're gonna what?
他们把我们当成狗屎 我们还由他们这样
They are treating us like shit and we're allowing them.
这些政客只会对压力做出回应
No, politicians, the only thing they really respond to is pressure
你听到他说的了吧 "3000个西区的电话"?
You heard him with his "3,000 West Side calls."
我们叫得还不够大声!
We're not yelling loud enough!
拿上你的东西
Get your stuff.
- 汤米 - 汤米 我是内德
- This is Tommy. - Tommy, it's Ned.
- 嘿 - 尼克死了
- Hey. - Nick died.
见鬼
Shit.
该死的
God damn.
我晚点再告诉你纪念仪式的安排
I'll call later when I know more about the memorial.
我有一个传统
I have this tradition.
当我认识的朋友死后我会做的事
It's something I do now when a friend dies.
我把他的名片保留下来
I save his Rolodex card.
不然怎么办?
What am I supposed to do?
扔进垃圾桶吗?
Throw it away in the trash can?
我不会那样做
I won't do that.
我不会
No, I won't.
那太决绝
That's too final.
去年我保留了5张名片
Last year I had five cards.
现在我有50张了
Now I have 50.
像一个纸片做的墓碑展览
A collection of cardboard tombstones
用橡皮筋捆在一起
bound together with a rubber band.
我恨死这些葬礼了
I hate these fuckin' funerals.
真的恨
I really do.
知道我还恨什么吗?
And you know what else I hate?
我恨悼念仪式
I hate the memorials.
都变成我们的社交生活了
That's our social life now.
参加这些活动
Going to these things.
尼克是个编舞师
Nick was a choreographer.
我不晓得你们知不知道
I don't know if any of you knew that.
他的事业刚起步 他没告诉过很多人
He was just starting out. He didn't tell a lot of people.
他期待着有一天
He was waiting to invite you to his
能邀请你们观看他在卡内基的盛大首场秀 (纽约著名音乐厅)
big debut at Carnegie Hall or some shit
你们会为他无比骄傲
so we could all be proud of him.
他那么优秀
But he was so good.
前途那么光明
He had such promise.
我们正在失去整整一代人
We're losing an entire generation.
刚开始的年轻人
Young men at the beginning.
就这么走了
Just gone.
编舞师 剧作家
Choreographers, playwrights
舞者 演员
dancers, actors.
这些剧本再也不会完成了
All those plays that won't get written now.
这些舞蹈再也不会被跳了
All those dances never to be danced.
最后 我只想说我在狂怒
In closing, I'm just gonna say I'm mad.
真的狂怒
I'm fuckin' mad.
我心里不断尖叫 "为什么他们任我们死去?"
I keep screaming inside, "Why are they letting us die?"
"为什么没人肯帮我们?"
"Why is no one helping us?"
而事实就是
And here's the truth.
答案就是
Here's the answer.
他们就是不喜欢我们
They just don't like us.
我要战胜这个
I'm going to beat this.
我一直都很幸运
I've always been lucky.
很好 这种态度就对了
Good. That's the right attitude.
我想在"时报"找工作 我找到了
I wanted a job on the "Times," I got it.
我想要内德
I wanted Ned.
我有过给内德吗?
Have I given it to Ned?
我不知道
I don't know.
一个人感冒了
One person has a cold
他的伴侣有时候会感染 有时不会
sometimes the partner catches it, sometimes not.
有医生说用安全套就不会有事
Some doctors are saying it's okay if we use condoms.
我知道他们这么说
I know they are.
- 我们还能接吻吗? - 菲尼克斯
- Can we kiss? - Felix.
你没有作战的武器
You have nothing to fight back with.
就是说你没有免疫系统
You have no immune system to speak of.
你的身体现在对各种可能的感染开放
Your body is now open to every conceivable type of infection.
你必须谨慎
You must be careful.
我会尽我最大的努力 你也要
I'm going to do my damnedest, so must you.
我敢说你对所有男孩都这么说
I bet you say that to all the boys.
事实上
As a matter of fact
是这样
I do.
噢 上帝
Oh, God.
很早很早以前 有个小男孩
Once upon a time there was a little boy
一心想爱上另一个小男孩
who always wanted to love another little boy.
有一天他终于找到了他的爱
One day he finally found that love
那种感觉好极了
and it was wonderful.
我该戴上手套
I'm supposed to use gloves.
我该做这个 我该做那个
I'm supposed to do this. I'm supposed to do that.
我不该亲吻他
I'm supposed to not kiss him.
- 对不起 - 不该只是一个45岁的男人
- I'm so sorry. - I'm not supposed to be only 45 years old
照顾一个35岁的年轻男人
and taking care of a 35-year-old young man
他看着像有100岁 而且快死了
who's 100 years old and dying.
艾玛说这就是跷跷板
Emma calls it a seesaw.
一会儿好 一会儿坏
He's fine, he gets sick
好些了…
he gets better...
又变得更糟
he gets sicker.
上帝 救救我
God help me.
他害怕我离开他
He's afraid I'll leave him.
我告诉他我不会离开他
I told him I wouldn't leave him.
我一秒钟都没想过要离开他
That I never for one second would think of leaving him.
可他不相信我
But he doesn't believe me.
在这个年代很难相信了
It's hard to believe in much these days.
但我们必须永远不要停止相信彼此
But we must never stop believing in each other.
我一团糟 这就是我
I'm a mess. That's what I am.
你哭啊哭 觉得已经哭不出来了
You cry and you cry until you think can't cry anymore
然后你又哭出更多
and then you cry some more.
不只为自己或菲尼克斯 而是为所有小男孩
Not only for yourself or Felix, but for all the little boys
那些终于找到了其他小男孩
who finally found their other little boys
这辈子期望的 而且变成了男人
they've wanted all their lives now that we're men.
男同志健康危机组织
G.M.H.C.
我是埃斯特拉 能为你做什么?
Estelle speaking. How may I assist you?
有人需要立遗嘱!
Someone needs a will!
- 内德在哪儿? 我要和他说话 - 他在里面
- Where's Ned? I want to speak to him. - He's in the back.
- 给他这个号码 - 谢谢
- Here, give him this number. - Thank you.
- 男同志健康危机组织 - 男同志健康危机组织
- G.M.H.C. - G.M.H.C.
汤米 我想我找到了4个合格的义务社工
Tommy, I think I got us maybe four qualified social workers to volunteer
- 全是拉拉 - 谢天谢地谢拉拉
- They're all lesbians. - Thank God for the lesbians.
你直肠?
Your anus?
噢 天王星啊
Oh, Planet Uranus.
感谢分享
Thank you for sharing.
米奇 你为什么不在里约热内卢?
Mickey, why aren't you in Rio?
我把电话设成自动接听了 大家该休息一会儿了
I put the phones on service. You guys should get some rest.
我们不想大家透支
We don't want any burnouts.
晚安 菲尔 谢谢你
Good night, Phil. Thank you.
晚安 宝贝
Night, honey.
- 拜 宝贝 - 晚安 甜心
- Bye, baby. - Good night, sweetheart.
今天工作很棒
Good work today.
好的
All right.
菲尔今天确诊了
Phil got diagnosed today.
米奇 为什么你不在里约热内卢度假?
Mickey, why aren't you on vacation in Rio?
我本来在 格里高利...
I was in Rio. Gregory...
和我一起在里约
and I were in Rio.
然后我接到了希拉姆从办公室打来的电话
I get a call from Hiram's office
说我今天一大早该去他的办公室
saying I should be in his office right away first thing this morning
从里约赶回来? 什么样的见面?
From Rio? What kind of meeting?
我去了市政厅 希勒姆让我一直等
I get to City Hall, Hiram keeps me waiting forever.
最后一个官员出来对我说
And finally the commissioner comes out and he says
希拉姆不愿意见我了
that Hiram doesn't want to see me anymore.
我想大吼 "我两天都没睡觉 混球白痴"
I wanted to scream, "I haven't slept in two days, you dumb fuck."
但我没有 我说
But I didn't. Instead I said,
"那么请问 先生...
"Please, sir, then...
为什么他大老远让我从里约赶回来?"
why did he make me come all the way back from Rio?"
他说 "恐怕他不便向我透露了"
And he says, "Oh, I'm afraid he didn't take me into his confidence."
然后他就走了
And he walks off.
内德攻击希拉姆的文章刚发表了
Ned's article attacking Hiram just came out.
我不想因为内德的自憎丢掉我的工作
I'm not going to lose my job because Ned doesn't like himself.
是什么 米克?
What's that, Mick?
你逼我们说一些我们不想说的话
You keep trying to get us to say things that we don't wanna say
我们没法承担在交到足够朋友前
and I don't think we can afford
树立太多的敌人
to make so many enemies before we have enough friends.
特里·斯保丁从氧气舱里
Terry Spaulding is calling all of his friends
跟他的所有朋友打电话告别
from under his oxygen tank to say goodbye.
蒂比·毛瑞尔服药过量死
Tibby Maurer took an overdose.
哈尔·谢克特的双脚现在假肢
Hal Schechter has got stumps for feet.
- 弗兰尼·桑图萨已经疯了! - 你能停停吗 停一停!
- Frannie Santuzza's lost his mind! - Will you stop it? Just stop!
- 米奇 你没事吧? - 我不觉得
- Mickey, you all right? - I don't think so.
为什么人们找不到病毒?
Why can't they find the virus?
宝贝 那个需要时间
Baby, it takes time.
我整天为市政做的事情…
I work all day for the city writing stuff on...
就是对比母乳喂养与婴儿食品
breast-feeding versus formula
得了疱疹要如何保持冷静
and how to stay calm when you have herpes.
晚上我会给我们的"本土人"写简报和健康专栏
And at night I work on our newsletter and our health column for the "Native."
我真的…真的受不了了
I just... I can't take it anymore.
我写到了每一种理论
I have written about every single theory.
病毒的反复感染
Repeated infection by a virus.
休眠病毒的新形态
New appearance by a dormant virus.
单病毒 新病毒 老病毒 多病毒 部分病毒
Single virus, new virus, old virus, multi-virus, partial virus,
- 潜伏病毒 变异病毒... - 放轻松 宝贝
- latent virus, mutant virus... - Tommy: Take it easy, honey.
我们一定不要忘了做爱 吹箫
No, we mustn't forget about fucking and sucking
接吻 血液 巫毒
and kissing and blood and voodoo
毒品 大麻 针头
and drugs and poppers and needles
非洲 海地 古巴 黑人
and Africa, Haiti, Cuba, blacks
变形虫 猪 还有他妈的天王星!
amoebas, pigs, fucking Uranus!
- 假如这些都不是原因呢? - 我不知道
- What if it isn't any of them? - I don't know.
伦敦大瘟疫 起源于一口水泵
The great plague of London was caused by drinking water from a pump
没有人...没有人注意到它
that just nobody... nobody noticed it.
也许是注定 或者是羊群理论...
Maybe it's predisposition or the theory of the herd...
只有很多人感染了 死够了才算完
only so many of us are going to get it, then the pool's used up.
万一是单一配偶的问题呢? 布鲁斯 你和我
What if it's monogamy? Bruce, you and I
我们甚至可能更糟
could actually be worse off
因为会被单一来源狂轰滥炸…
because of constant bombardment from a single source...
来自我们的爱人
our lovers.
也许那些去浴室的男人
So maybe the guys who go to the baths
也许他们建立了最好的免疫系统
maybe they've built up the best immunity.
我不知道怎么回答每个人 每个人都在问我
I don't know what to tell anybody anymore and everybody asks me.
谁是对的? 我不知道
Who's right? I don't know.
谁是错的? 我感觉...
Who's wrong? I feel...
感觉他妈的无助死了
I feel so fucking inadequate.
我们怎样对人们说 "停止"?
How can we tell people, "Stop"?
我不…它可能是因为...
It's just... I don't... it might be caused by...
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我完全就是这种感觉
That's exactly how I feel.
也许他是对的
And maybe he's right.
而这更让我害怕
And that scares me.
内德 你让我害怕
Neddy, you scare me.
你真的觉得总统...
You really think the president...
他希望这一切发生? 你真的相信中情局
that he wants this to happen? You really think the CIA
发动了细菌战
has unleashed germ warfare
来杀死杰瑞·法威尔厌恶的所有玻璃? (极端右翼政客)
to kill off all the queers that Jerry Falwell doesn't want?
- 米奇 冷静下来 - 怎么冷静?
- Mick. Try to hold on. - To what?
我曾经爱我的国家
I used to love my country.
"本土人"杂志收到一封匿名信
The "Native" received an anonymous letter describing
说国防部在马里兰州的迪特里克堡进行一项绝密实验…
top-secret Defense Department experiments at Fort Detrick, Maryland...
生产了一种能破坏免疫系统的病毒
that have produced a virus that can destroy the immune system.
代号是"强硬之手"
Its codename was "Firm Hand."
他们从1978年开始在一群同志身上做实验
They started testing it in 1978 on a group of gays.
我从来不相信这些的...
I never used to believe shit like that...
他们想迫害死我们!
they're gonna persecute us!
他们会取消我们的医疗保险
They're gonna cancel our health insurance
把我们关进集中营 隔离起来
they're gonna put us into camps, they're gonna quarantine us.
你觉得我是凶手吗?
And you think that I'm killing people?
- 我没那么说 - 你心里清楚你是这么想
- That is not what I said. - It is, you know you said it.
我这辈子花了15年
I've spent 15 years of my life
为我们的权利而战斗
fighting for our right to be free
好让我们自由的做爱 无论时间和地点
and to make love wherever, whenever.
现在你跟我说 我这么多年的努力
And you're telling me all those years
那些作为同志所代表的都是错误!
of what being gay stood for is wrong!
我成了凶手
And that I'm a murderer.
我们曾经那么灰暗 你忘了吗?
We have been so oppressed. Don't you remember?
你不能看到这有多重要吗 我们能够公开的相爱
Can't you see how important it is for us to love openly
不需要躲藏 不需要负罪?
without hiding, without guilt?
你为什么不能看到?
Why can't you see that?
我去过帝国大厦顶层
I went to the top of the Empire State Building.
好了 我送你回家
Okay, I'm taking you home.
你可以从那儿跳下去 没人管你
You can jump off from there when nobody's looking.
好了 米奇 我们回家 现在就回家
All right, Mickey, let's go home. Right now.
内德 我不是凶手 我不是
Ned, I'm not a murderer. I'm not.
我这辈子都被人恨 因为是同志
All my life I've been hated for being gay
因为个子矮
for being short
因为是犹太人
Jewish.
所以你跟别人说吧
So go ahead, you tell everybody.
跟所有人说我们错了 我很抱歉
Tell everybody that we were wrong and I'm sorry.
总有一天 总有个人会出现
Someday, somebody's gonna come along
他会狠狠捅你一刀
and they're gonna stick the knife in you
跟你说 你这辈子付出的一切 你的一生都是浪费!
and tell you everything you fought for your whole life is shit!
米奇!
Mickey!
米奇!住手!
Mickey! Get up!
- 住手  来这儿 – 没事了
- Get up. Come here. - It's okay.
来
Come on.
我现在送你回家 好吗?
I'm gonna take you home now, okay?
我不想回家 送我去圣文森医院
I don't wanna go home. Take me to St. Vincent's.
好的 来吧 我们走
Okay. That's fine. Come. Let's go.
听我说 我们都很累了 听到了吗?
Look, we're all real tired, you hear me?
我们这儿的负能量都快爆表了
We got ourselves here a lot of bereavement overload.
我们是战士 不是吗?
We're the fighters. Aren't we?
- 我们是… - 当然是 亲爱的
We're the fi... - You bet, sweetness.
而且你是英雄 听到了吗?
And you're a hero. YOU HEAR ME?
不管你知不知道 你都是个英雄
You're a hero whether you know that or not.
你是我们的第一个英雄
You're our first hero.
我们走
Let's go.
你想做主席吗?
You wanna be president?
我只想菲尼克斯活下来
I just want Felix to live.
男同健康危机组织
Gay Men's Health Crisis.
海勒姆 老伙计 还好吗?
Hiram, old buddy. How's it hanging?
嗯
Mm.
- 准备好了? - 嗯
- You ready? - Yeah.
市长找到一笔小的秘密资金
The mayor's found a secret little fund
可以秘密的拨给我们
for giving away money secretly.
我们不能告诉任何人钱从哪儿来
We are not allowed to tell anyone where we got it,
如果我们说了 就再也不会有
and if we do, we'll never get any more.
- 多少? - 9千块
- How much? - $9,000.
内德
Ned.
埃尔伯特死了
Albert's dead.
他妈妈想在他死前 在凤凰城见他最后一面
His mother wanted to see him in Phoenix before he died.
很明显他只剩最后一周了
And this was the last week, when it was obvious.
我拿到了艾玛的许可证明 带他去机场
So I got permission from Emma and took him to the airport.
等我们上了飞机
And when we got to the airport
机长拒绝驾驶
the pilot refused to fly the plane.
而我拒绝下飞机
So I refused to get off of it.
你在的话肯定会为我骄傲 内德
You would have been very proud of me, Ned.
最后终于换了一个机长
So finally we get another pilot
当飞机起飞后
and when we take off
埃尔伯特开始失控了
Albert just loses his mind.
我不想呆在这儿
I don't wanna be in this thing.
- 没事 – 我不想呆在这地方…
It's okay. - I don't wanna be in this...
- 我要下去 – 别 埃尔伯特
- I'm just gonna go. - No, Albert.
我不想…
I don't wanna...
- 埃尔伯特 – 让他坐下
- Albert. - Tell him to sit down.
- 不好意思 – 先生 先生 你得坐好
- I'm sorry. - Sir, sir, you have to keep seated.
- 快坐下 - 先生 请你坐下 你得…
- Sit down up there. - Sir, have a seat. You have to...
不!
No!
- 先生… - 停下!
- Sir... - Stop!
先生!
Sir!
我们坐下 好吗?
We gotta sit down, okay?
他认不出我了
He doesn't recognize me.
是我 是我
It's me. It's me.
也不知道我们要去哪儿
Doesn't know where we're going.
- 我们就快到了 – 不知道我们要去凤凰城
- We're almost home. - That we're going to see his mother
见他妈妈… 什么都不知道
in Phoenix... nothing.
他变得….
He just becomes...
见鬼 能给一我条毛巾吗 谢谢?
Oh, shit. Can I get a goddamn towel, please?
等我们到达凤凰城 等我们到医院
When we land in Phoenix and when we get to the hospital
他母亲已经把房间收拾得很好…
where his mother had fixed up the room real nice...
埃尔伯特已经死了
Albert is dead.
医院的医生不愿给他尸检
The hospital doctors refused to examine him
在他的死亡证明上开具死亡原因
and give him a cause of death on his death certificate.
而没有死亡证明 殡仪馆就不肯收他
Without the death certificate, the undertakers will not take him.
- 警察也不管 – 哥们 拖它下来啊
- And neither would the police. - Come on, man. Pull it down.
终于一个护理员进来 把我的埃尔伯特
Finally some orderly comes in and stuffs my Albert
塞进一个大号的垃圾袋
in an oversized Glad garbage bag
把他和其他垃圾一起丢进巷子里的垃圾堆
and puts him in the alley with the rest of the garbage.
我帮了你一个大忙 我把他弄了出来
I did you a favor, man. I got him out.
我要50块
I want 50 bucks.
- 这是全部的骨灰? - 是的
- Is that all of him? - Yep.
你要? 3千块
You want him? $3,000.
他走了 走了
He's gone. He's gone.
去了
Gone.
我的天
Oh, God.
我跟你们说 他们在谋杀我们
I am telling you they are murdering us
而我们让他们这样
and we are letting them.
我们都会死
We're gonna die.
我们很快都会死
We're gonna die very soon
除非你们都他妈的站起来还击
unless you get off your fucking asses and fight back."
艾玛在那儿等着
Emma's in there waiting.
来 就两口 来
Come on, two bites. Come on, now.
- 不 不  – 别让我拿酸奶出气
- No. - Don't make me break out the yogurt.
- 再一口 – 你跟你哥哥和好了吗?
- One more. - Have you talked to your brother yet?
我记得你的这个样子
I remember that about you.
你不跟这个世界上你最爱的人说话
You don't talk to the people you love most in the world.
你想我好起来 但我好不起来
You want me to get better and I'm not getting better
我感到特别他妈的内疚
and I feel so fucking guilty.
你周五跟比尔·布拉斯有个午餐预约
You have a lunch meeting with Bill Blass on Friday.
- 高档啊 – 嗯…
- Fancy. - Mm...
我会打给他致歉
I'll call with my regrets.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
跟你订一个两月后的约会
Making a date with you two months from now.
我被邀请去耶鲁的同志一周演讲
I've been invited to speak at Yale's Gay Week.
我们会一起去 记得我跟你说过现在他们的那些舞会吗?
And we're going. Remember how I told you they have those dances there now?
你是我的舞伴
You're my date.
我太想要你活下来
I want you to live so much.
也许我不该说出来
I'm not supposed to say that.
上帝啊 求你再给我们一年
Oh, please, God. Give us one more year.
我保证会吃菠菜
I promise I'll eat my spinach.
我医治的
I am taking care
这个疾病的患者数量
of more victims of this disease
超过世界上所有人
than anyone in the world.
我有更多冷藏血样
We have more frozen blood samples
更多各种数据
more data of every kind
和更多经验
and much more experience.
布鲁克娜医生 政府的立场是这样
Dr. Brookner, the government's position is this.
在5千5百万拨款项目中
There are $5 million in the pipeline for which we have received
我们有5百万准备发放
over $55 million worth of requests.
5百万对2000起病例来说并不怎么多
5 million doesn't seem quite right for some 2,000 cases.
光7个泰伦诺死亡的案例 政府就花了3百万来调查 (一种镇痛药)
The government spent 3 million investigating seven deaths from Tylenol
- 我们已经进入第三年了 – 我们投票驳回
- We're entering the third year. - We voted to reject
你的资金申请
your application for funding.
噢?
Oh?
我想听你们的理由
I'd like to hear your reasons.
你建议的研究方向
The direction of the research you're suggesting
不精确也没有重点
is imprecise and unfocused.
噢 这样啊 是吗?
Oh, it is, is it?
你对正发生的完全不比我知道得更多
You don't know what's going on any more than I do.
请告诉我究竟是为什么要阻碍我的研究?
Could you tell me precisely why you're blocking my efforts?
布鲁克娜医生 还有其他的研究员
Dr. Brookner. There are now other investigators.
这已经不是你一个人的疾病了 尽管你这么认为
This is no longer only your disease, though you seem to think it is.
噢 我是这么想的啊?
Oh, I do, do I?
所以你是来把它从我这儿拿走 是吗?
And you're here to take it away from me, is that it?
让我来告诉你一个小秘密 医生
Well, I'll let you in on a little secret, Doctor.
你可以拿走 我一开始就不想要它
You can have it. I didn't want it in the first place.
你觉得看着年轻人去死是一种殊荣?
You think it's a privilege to watch young men die?
我干嘛跟你争辩?
What am I arguing with you for?
你连蒸馏水都不知道是什么
You do not know enough to study boiled water.
你有什么资格过来对我评头论足?
How dare you come down here and judge me?!
我们只是应莫里医生请求来进行业内小组评估
We only serve on this peer review panel at the behest of Dr. Murray
又一个白痴 顺便说 还是深柜的同性恋
Another idiot... and, by the way, a closeted homosexual
竭尽他的所能把这一切扫进地毯下面
doing everything in his power to sweep this under the rug.
我还发过誓永远不在公众场合说这些
And I vowed I'd never say anything like that in public.
怎么总是这样
How does it always happen
总是白痴在这样的小组里面?
that all of the idiots are always on your team?
你们怎么能驳回我的研究资金申请
How can you refuse to fund my research
或者不邀请我参加你们的?
or not invite me to participate in yours?
你们的国家卫生研究所
Your National Institutes of Health
两年前就收到了我的第一份资金申请
received my first request for money two years ago.
你们花了一年时间把申请表打印出来
It took you one year just to print up application forms.
从我第一个上报案例算起 你们花了三年时间
It's taken you three years from my first reported case
过来这里看一眼 而微不足道的那一点钱
just to show up here for a look, and the paltry amount of money
你们逼我们去乞讨
you are forcing us to beg for
从你们每年收到的40亿经费里面
out of the $4 billion you now receive each and every year
施舍一点来捍卫美国人民的健康
to protect the health of American people
而且天知道它们时候到位
won't come to anyone before only God knows when.
法国已经发现了一种有可能相关的病毒
A promising virus has been discovered in France.
你们为什么拒绝跟法国人合作?
Why do you refuse to cooperate with the French?
为什么我们被告诫不得和法国人合作?
Why are we told not to cooperate with the French?
就为你们可以偷到诺贝尔奖
Just so you can steal a Nobel Prize
就让这种疾病流行 导致死亡吗!
while something is being passed around that causes death!
非洲已经发现了女性病例
Women have been discovered to have it in Africa
很明显这种病会在异性恋中传播
where it is clearly transmitted heterosexually.
只是时间的问题
It is only a question of time.
在你们做点什么之前我们可能都已经死了
We could all be dead before you do anything.
你要我的数据? 我的构想?
You want my data? You want my ideas?
我的病人? 拿去!
You want my patients? Take them!
我只求你能做点什么!
Just do something with them!
你说对了! 我是…
You're fucking right! I am...
不精确也没有重点 而你们是白痴!
imprecise and unfocused and you are all idiots!
你组织的对市长的抗议?
Did you organize that picketing of the mayor?
是的
Yes.
- 还有标语?- 是的
- And the signs? - Yes.
你的下一部戏据说是关于第一夫人
And your next play is about a First Lady
- 在好莱坞得到最好的口交 – 是的
- who gave the best blow jobs in Hollywood. - Yes.
- 这里做我们的新办公室再合适不过 – 是的
- This place is perfect for our new office. - Yes.
好干净
So tidy.
来
Here.
我来
I got him.
来 送你去床上躺躺
Come on. Let's get you back to bed.
好的
Okay.
就这样
Here you go.
埃斯特拉给你做了些等会儿吃的白菜卷
Estelle made you some stuffed cabbage for later.
巴黎已经有一种新药
There's this new drug in Paris.
凯斯勒的爱人飞去取了
Kessler's lover is flying out to get it.
这个 HPA-23
Here it is. HPA-23.
内德
Ned.
- 他情况很糟 – 你觉得这个真的有用吗
- He looks awful - You think this is anything
还是跟其他药一样的没用?
or is it just another shit drug like all the rest?
我觉得你得做好心理准备放手了
I think you need to prepare yourself for letting go.
你不能为自己爱的人放弃战斗
You can't stop fighting for the ones you love.
你就没有为自己爱的人而战过吗?
Haven't you ever had to fight for somebody you love?
汤米 你得试着站出来
Tommy. You gotta start putting yourself out there
这样别人才能看到我所看到的你
in a way that everyone else could see what I see.
这是什么狗屁做爱戏啊?
What kind of a fucked-up love scene is this?
喂?
Yes?
我是 女士?
Yes, ma'am?
明天4点半?
4:30 tomorrow?
好的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
他妈的白宫打来的
The fucking White House.
去他妈的市长 我刚被邀请去白宫了
Fuck the mayor. I've just been invited to the White House.
他们要行动了!
They're gonna do something!
我想搞清楚一下
Oh, just so I understand
你的这个头衔
what exactly does your title mean
约翰·布鲁诺
总统顾问
究竟可以对我们的瘟疫做些什么?
in terms of our plague?
我们不使用消极编制 那样只会吓到民众
We prefer not to use negative terms. It only scares people.
已经有3,339个病例了
Well, there's 3,339 cases so far.
1,122人死亡
1,122 dead.
对我来说这就是瘟疫 我被吓到了
Sounds like a plague to me. I'm scared.
你没有吗?
Aren't you?
你的头衔是什么意思来着?
What does your title mean again?
我给总统提供建议
I come up with ideas for the president
关于该做什么 不该做什么
about what he ought to be doing and not doing.
好的 收到
Okay, good. Got it.
所以 拨款还有对吧? 没有被花掉
So, the money's there, right? It just hasn't been spent.
现在法国有一种新药
So there's this new drug in France.
为什么国家卫生所不研究它?
Why doesn't the N.I.H. study it?
我是说 我想要的 我们想要的 我们亟需要的
I mean, what I want, what we want, what we desperately need
是有人帮助我们删减这些官样文章
is for somebody to help us cut through all this red tape.
我向你保证 我的每一周
I can asure you that not a week goes by
没有不向总统提供新信息和汇报情况的
that I don't bring new information and reports to the president.
关于这个病的进展已经很了不起了
The progress that's been made on this disease is unprecedented
可它会传染
But it's contagious.
你没看到就因为它会传染
Can't you see that because it's contagious
你们得…得尽快行动吗?
you... you have to work faster?
你真的觉得任何人
Do you really believe that anybody
在这个国家的公共政策人员心里面
in a serious public policy position in their heart of hearts
哪怕是它们最闭门的会议上
or even in their most closeted meetings
他们会对彼此说  "嘿 各位
says to each other, "Hey, guys,
我们还是别为这事太烦恼好吗?"
let's not get too upset about this"?
是的 你的老板现在还没大声说过"艾滋"这个词
Yes, your boss hasn't said the word "AIDS" out loud.
回答我一个问题
Answer me this one question.
这个病... 妓女可能得这个病吗?
This shit, can... can hookers get it?
或者 一夜情的人?
Or, you know, someone who had a one-night stand?
- 当然 – 你不能证明
- Of course. - You can't prove that.
我是说 从我了解到的和读到的来看
I mean, from what I understand, what I've read
男女性通过一般阴道交媾
female-to-male transmissions through normal
而传播的效率并不怎么高
vaginal intercourse does not seem to be very efficient.
不是这么简单 它是病毒 病毒不会歧视
It simply isn’t true, it's a virus, it doesn't discriminate.
是的 可是…
Yes, but...
传播起来很难 不是吗?
it's very difficult. Isn't it?
对一个直人来说
It's almost impossible for a straight, you know
一个普通异性恋男子来说几乎是不可能的 我说得对吗?
regular heterosexual guy to get it, am I right?
- 什么? - 还没有登记的病例 对吗?
- I'm sorry? - There's no documented cases, am I right?
没有一起登记的病例
There's not a single documented case
证明异性恋男子会得这个
of a heterosexual man getting it
无论通过做爱或是口交?
Not from fucking or a blow job?
我没有这方面的信息
I don't have that information.
很好 我也是这么想的
Great, that's what I thought.
苏珊 准备我的会议
Susan, call my meeting.
我会晚到15分钟 谢谢
I'll be about 15 minutes late. Thanks.
- 非常感谢你 –  等等
- Thank you so much. - Wait, please.
- 随时联系 – 先生 等等
- Call me anytime. - Sir. Wait.
预计会有1亿人感染
100 million predicted
可是没有人重视!
and nobody is paying any attention!
2楼需要保安
Hi, I need security on the second floor.
你干嘛坐在地上?
Why you sitting on the floor?
我摔倒了 在从这头到那头的途中
I fell down trying to get from there to here.
别碰我 我的天
Oh, don't touch me! God.
我讨厌你那样看着我
I hate it when you look at me.
饿了吗? 我饿了 你呢?
You hungry? I'm hungry, how about you?
我看了我约会簿里的所有人
I looked in all my datebooks.
其他和我睡过的人都没得病
No one else I slept with is sick.
也许你才是携带者
Maybe you're the carrier.
我们不需要这样对彼此
We don't have to do this to each other.
菲尼克斯 你会好起来 你会的
You're gonna get better, Felix. You are.
艾玛说国家卫生所终于开始研究了
Emma says the N.I.H. is finally starting research.
- 我们得抱着希望 – 噢 是吗?
- We have to hope. - Oh, do we?
- 是的 – 是吗? 我能做什么?
- Yes, we do. - Do we? And how am I supposed to do that?
别吃那些垃圾食品!
Stop eating that shit!
- 给我 – 不!
- Give it to me. - No!
你知道保持营养的重要性
You know how important it is to watch your nutrition.
我的寿命预期只有10分钟
I have a life expectancy of 10 more minutes.
我想吃什么就吃什么
I'll eat what I wanna eat.
内德
Ned.
我越来越差了 好吗?
It's getting messier. Okay?
我不想你看着我死
I don't wanna make you see it.
没人能逼我做任何事
Nobody can make me do anything.
你该比其他人都更知道这个
You should know that better than anybody.
你准备剩下的日子都坐在那个地板上吗?
Now you gonna sit there on the floor for the rest of your life?
- 听到我说的了吗? - 你听到我说的了吗?
- Do you hear me? - Do you hear me?
- 没有! - 没有?
- No! - No?
我已经接受超过40种治疗 没有?
I've had over 40 treatments. No?
我做了3种…不 4种不同化疗 没有!
I've had three... no, four different kinds of chemo. No!
我试过3种实验药
I've had three different experimentals.
艾玛花在我身上的时间比任何人都多
Emma has spent more time on me than anyone else.
可什么用也没有!
And it hasn't done a thing!
你总不能强迫太阳出来!
You cannot force the goddamn sun to come out!
我受够了那些争吵
I am so sick of fighting
所有人的愚蠢
and everybody's stupidity
盲目还有负罪感之旅
and blindness and guilt trips.
这些东西你不吃? 那就别吃了
You can't eat the food? Don't eat the food.
我不管了 吃你的毒药 我不管了
I don't care. Take your poison, I don't care.
鱼对你身体有益
Fish is good for you.
不想吃 对吗?
Don't want any of that, do we?
绿色莎拉也不要了!
No green salad!
西兰花不要了! 蔬菜不要了!
No broccoli! No vegetables!
带7种谷物的面包也不要了!
No bread with seven grain!
怎么会有人想喝牛奶呢?
Why would anyone ever want any milk?
反正你骨头里面有钙了!
You might get some calcium in your bones!
你想死吗 菲尼克斯?
Do you wanna die, Felix?
死吧!
Die!
求你了 别离开我 菲尼克斯
Please don't leave me, Felix.
走开! 走开!
Keep out! Keep out!
走开!
Keep out!
混球些
Assholes.
男同健康危机组织
Gay Men's Health Crisis.
鹅口疮是种真菌 是的
Thrush is a fungus, yes.
你告诉他我们会在那儿抗议
Can you tell him that we'll be picketing there
而且不怕逮捕或警察暴力
and not afraid of arrest or police brutality.
- 男同健康危机组织 - 是的
- Gay Men's Health Crisis. - That's right.
市长还有4小时
The mayor has four more hours before we carry out
如果他不见我们 我们就行使非暴力不合作
our threats of civil disobedience if he doesn't meet with us.
汤米昨天收到电话了 内德
Tommy got the call yesterday, Ned.
你怎么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?!
你看 我说了能行!
You see, it works!
- 什么时候? 什么时候? - 只有两个人可以去见市长 内德
- When? When? - Only two can go to the meeting, Ned.
- 什么时候? - 汤米是执行董事
- When? - Tommy's executive director.
我要去
I'm going.
- 我会提董事会投票 内德  – 我写给市长的
- I polled the fucking board, Ned. - I wrote that letter
那封信 那个会面是我的
to the mayor. That meeting is mine.
我要代表这个组织去那儿
I am going to go and represent this organization
这个我把生命的每分钟都花在为它战斗上面
that I have spent every minute of my life fighting for
在我的客厅成立的组织
and that was started in my living room
不然我就不干了
or I quit.
你想要我不干?
You'd let me quit?
董事会要我大声对你念这个
The board asked me to read this out loud to you.
- 念什么? - 这封信
- Read what? - A letter.
好 你读啊
Go on, read it.
我们已经广泛传阅这封信
"We are circulating this letter widely among people
在有判断力和良好认知的人当中
of judgment and good sense.
我们必须制止你庞大的个人主义膨胀
You are on a colossal ego trip we must curtail.
反复一而再的玩弄恐惧
To manipulate fear as you have done repeatedly
对我们来说 是完全粗暴的行径
is to us, sheer barbarism.
将同志的死加以占用
To exploit the deaths of gay men as you have done
在全美的电视和出版物上兜售
on television and in publications all over America
对我们来说 是一种破坏
is to us, an act of vandalism.
而在性解放多年后
And after years of liberation
你让我们再对性感到肮脏…
you helped make sex dirty again for us...
可怕和成为禁忌
terrible and forbidden.
我们对你的愤怒
We are more angry at you
超过我们对生命中的任何人
than ever in our lives toward anyone.
我们觉得你想要领导我们
We think you want to lead us all.
可是…
Well...
我们不想要你来领导
we do not want you to lead us.
根据由威克斯 弗兰克尔 莱温施泰起草的章程
In accordance with our bylaws as drawn up by Weeks, Frankel, Levinstein
内德先生将被免除
Mr. Ned Weeks is hereby removed
男同健康危机组织的董事职务
as a director of Gay Men's Health Crisis.
我们乞求你安静的离开我们
We beg that you leave us quietly
别毁掉我们和我们从事的美好事业
and not destroy us and what good work we manage
无论你赞不赞成
despite your disapproval.
立即生效
Effective immediately."
内德
Ned.
执行董事不在董事会里 你知道的
The executive director isn't on the board, you know that.
我没有投票权
I don't have a vote.
我能做什么?
What could... what could I have done?
- 你没支持我 – 不是那样
- You didn't support me. - That's not true.
你们都在从事殡仪业
You're all nothing but undertakers.
整个组织就是个殡仪馆
This whole organization is a funeral parlor.
- 内德… - 你们做的全部就是照顾死者
Ned... - All you do is take care of the dying.
谁来为活着的人战斗 好让他们继续活着?
Who's fighting so the living can go on living?
谁来为我的菲尼克斯战斗?
Who's fighting for my Felix?
汤米 我们需要你去楼上
Tommy. We need you upstairs.
我属于的地方 有马塞尔·普鲁斯特
I belong to a culture that includes Marcel Proust
沃尔特·惠特曼 田纳西·威廉斯 亚历山大大帝 (均为同性恋名人)
Walt Whitman, Tennessee Williams, Alexander the Great
还有很多你不敢相信的教皇和主教
so many popes and cardinals you wouldn't believe.
特种部队先生 你知道是一个公开出柜的英国同志
Mr. Green Beret, did you know that it was an openly gay Englishman
令第二次世界大战获胜的吗?
who's responsible for winning World War II?
他的名字叫艾伦·图灵 他破解了恩尼格玛
His name's Alan Turing and he cracked the Germans' Enigma code.
战争结束后他自杀了
After the war was over, he committed suicide
因为他为是同志饱受折磨
because he was so hounded for being gay.
为什么他们从来不在学校里教这些?
Why didn't they teach any of that in schools?
因为一个同志我们才取得二战的胜利!
A gay man is responsible for winning World War II!
如果他们这样做了 也许他就不会自杀
If they did, maybe he wouldn't have killed himself
你也不会这么害怕做真实的自己
and you wouldn't be so terrified of who you are.
这也是我希望被人记住的
That's how I want to be remembered.
作为一个赢得了战争的人
As one of the men who won the war.
布鲁斯 我知道我是个混球
Bruce, I know that I am an asshole.
但请不要把我拒之门外
But please don't shut me out.
走吧
Go.
你弟弟和我是恋人
Your brother and I are lovers.
我要死了 我想立一份遗嘱
I'm dying and I need to make a will.
- 请坐 – 谢谢
- Please. - Thank you.
我想把所有东西都留给内德
I want to leave everything to Ned.
- 我弟弟还好吗? – 他把所有事都怪在自己头上
- How's my brother? - Well, he blames himself for everything
从我要死了 到整个世界的局势
from my dying to the state of the entire world.
这些 加上你们仍然不讲话
All that plus you two still not talking.
你肯定跟他一样倔
You must be as stubborn as he is.
我会尽快打给他
I'll call him right away.
就现在 他正在家收拾行李
Do. He's at home packing.
我们要去耶鲁几天
We're going to Yale in a few days.
参加同志一周
For Gay Week.
他说他都不敢相信
He says he can't believe it.
他在那儿读大一时差点自杀
He tried to kill himself there when he was a freshman.
我没多少留下...
I haven't much...
除了一块漂亮的地
except for a beautiful piece of land
在威尔佛力特的海角 (马萨诸塞州)
on the Cape in Wellfleet.
内德不知道这个
Ned doesn't know about it.
本来想作为惊喜给他的
It was to have been a surprise
等我们去那儿定居
for when we lived there together
从此快乐的生活在一起
riding away happily ever after.
我还有一张保单
I also have an insurance policy
跟”时报”签的 我是记者...
uh... with the "Times." I'm a reporter...
纽约时报的记者
for "The New York Times."
该留给我的最近亲人的
It's meant to come to my next of kin.
我怕他们不会给他
I'm afraid they might not give it to him.
如果他被列为受益人 他们必须给他
Well, if he's listed as a beneficiary, they must.
你知道这个世界怎样 别这么天真
You're smarter than that. Don't be so naive.
我向你保证 我会尽我的一切保证它履行
I assure you, I will fight to make sure that they do.
我在等你这句话
I was hoping you'd say that.
菲尼克斯…
Felix...
要是能早认识你就好了
I wish we'd met sooner.
我应该穿白色的衣服
I should be wearing something white
你是穿的白色衣服 亲爱的
You are, honey.
应该…应该是
It should... it should be something
派瑞·艾力斯为我个人定制的 (美国著名男装设计师)
Perry Ellis ran up for me personally.
内德?
Ned?
你要想办法再次战斗
You find a way to fight again.
我会的
I will.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿
Hey.
艾玛 艾玛…
Emma. Emma...
我们… 我们能开始了吗?
Could we... could we start now, please?
我们在这儿 在上帝的注视下
We are gathered here in the sight of God
为这两位男士结合作证
to join together these two men.
他们爱对方
They love each other
非常的深 而且…
very much and...
希望在他们的家人面前 朋友面前 结合
want to be married in the presence of their family and friends
我没看到异议
I see no objection.
你 菲尼克斯·特勒
Do you, Felix Turner
- 接受内德·威克斯… – 我的亚历山大 我愿意
- take Ned Weeks..." - Alexander. Yeah.
- 成为你的... – 我最好 最真的爱
- To be your... - My great true love.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意 我愿意
I do. I do.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意 我愿意
I do. I do.
我是汤米
This is Tommy.
谢谢跟我说
Thanks for letting me know.
"The Only Living Boy In New York” (Simon & Garfunkel)
耶鲁同志周
Q
■
A
F
O
N
E
同志亦凡人中文站
翻译  安为 丑博士 小p
校对  小P
特效压制  豆子在旅行
罗纳德·里根总统直到1985年9月17日才第一次公开提到艾滋病
在一个新闻会议上宣称艾滋病研究为“最优先任务”
事实上1986年里根提交的联邦预算反而削减11%艾滋开支
1986年底公布的死亡数据为24599人
自从1981年疾病爆发后 全世界有3600万人死于HIV/艾滋
每天有超过6000例新感染的HIV